<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">philrefo</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018096</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Philosophia Reformata</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Association for Reformational Philosophy</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00318035</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23528230</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24710030</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ON WORLDVIEWS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Sander</given-names>
                  <surname>Griffioen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">77</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24710027</issue-id>
         <fpage>19</fpage>
         <lpage>56</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Association for Reformational Philosophy</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24710030"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This is a study in the philosophy of worldview. It consists of two parts. The first part, which is presented here, is concerned primarily with key elements in the general structure of a worldview. It lays the groundwork for more concrete and differentiated investigations that will be pursued as a sequel to this article. The genius of the worldview notion is that it signifies both an inner conviction and an outlook on the world. Thus it combines the personal and the universal. Moreover, it does so in the context of conflicting convictions and outlooks. Accordingly, the plural worldviews is more adequate than the singular since each reflects the presence of the others. As I try to show, this inherent pluralism is what is missing both in traditional settings as well as under totalitarian regimes. The main body of this article consists of an analysis of four basic functions: 'orientation', 'assent' (i.e. a channeling of convictions), 'integration', and 'public recognition' (i.e. attaining recognition for a cause). A preceding section is dedicated to a delineation of worldview with respect to 'world picture'. Special attention is paid in this connection to 'embedded' worldviews: hybrid forms characteristic for our present 'post-worldview era'.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1198e114a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e121" publication-type="other">
The sequel to this article, to be published later, has a full section on the critique of
Heidegger, Bakhtin, Adorno and others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e131a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e138" publication-type="other">
See the special worldview issue of Pro Peg? (Dordt College, Sioux Center, Iowa), especially
the essays by Lief (2010) and Sibley (2010). See also Smith (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e148a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e155" publication-type="other">
The Shorter Oxford Dictionary has: 'world view: a set of fundamental beliefs, attitudes, values,
etc., determining or constituting a comprehensive outlook on life, the universe, etc.' (SOED
2007, entry: world)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e168a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e175" publication-type="other">
"Der Inbegriff der Gedanken, Vorstellungen, Ideen eines Menschen uber das Ganze der
Welt und seine Stellung in ihr."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e186a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e193" publication-type="other">
There is some evidence that German Weltanschauung was first used as a translation of
weretdbeschouuring (Vandci horn 2009, §2.1), whereas in Dutch urereld- en leirensbeschoutiring ('world-
and life-view') and leoensovertuiging are up to the present day at least as popular as
wenddbeschouiiring.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e209a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e216" publication-type="other">
A controversial issue is whether or not it is right to say that the Biblical narratives are
placed against the backdrop of contemporary Wellbilder. see Gousmett (2011, 129).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e226a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e233" publication-type="other">
Remarkably enough, Dijksterhuis' classic The Mechanization of the Wodd Picture only briefly
dwelled on the meaning of 'world picture'; the author simply equated this term with 'a way of
looking' ('beschouwingswijze') (2006, Part I, par. 2).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e246a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e253" publication-type="other">
Rickert (1921, 170) puts this distinction in terms of Sein ('is') and Gelten ('to be valid', 'to
hold true'): 'Je klarer der Unterschied von realem Sein und irrealem Gelten zutage tritt, um so
unabhângiger muB die Weltanschauung von dem Wirklichkeitsbild werden, das die Natur-
wissenschaften und die Geschichte entwerfen.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e269a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e276" publication-type="other">
Koestler (1941, 144) chose this as motto for the final chapter of his Darkness at Noon.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e283a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e290" publication-type="other">
See Berger and Luckmann (1967) on plausibility structures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e298a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e305" publication-type="other">
According to Hendrik van Riessen's (1967) analysis secularization owes its success to an
'effective semblance' ('werkzame schijn') of being an autonomous process that cannot be
stopped or reversed; see also Griffioen (2008, 80-81). The absence of alternatives I am dealing
with here is another illustration of an 'effective semblance'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e321a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e328" publication-type="other">
I remember Albert Wolters speaking in this connection of 'broad categorical distinc-
tions'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e338a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e345" publication-type="other">
Compare Timothy Keller (2008, 15) 'What is religion then? It is a set of beliefs that
explain what life is all about, who we are, and the most important things that human beings
should spend their time doing'. He rightly adds: 'some call this a "worldview"'. The ancient
Chinese understood the relevance of this distinction, to wit this statement from an encyclo-
pedia compiled in 239 BC: 'When the difference between insignificance and importance is not
understood, the important becomes insignificant and the insignificant important. When this
situation prevails, every action ends in failure.' (Knoblock and Riegel 2000, section 1/2.1) The
Chinese text has 'heavy' (zlurng) for 'important' and 'light'(φηφ for 'unimportant'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e374a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e381" publication-type="other">
Note that in the case of an ideology even maps may lose their complementarity; E.F.
Schumacher (1977, 1) relates that when visiting Leningrad in the 1960's he saw several
churches that were not shown on the map. The answer of the official guide was: 'we don't show
churches on our maps'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e397a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e404" publication-type="other">
By turning the all-of-life into a program, neo-Calvinism would not only disqualify itself as
worldview but would also contradict Bible texts implying a distinction between the essential
and the inessential, as for instance the apostle Paul's insistence that 'food does not bring us
near to God' (1 Cor. 8:8), and his avowal: Ί beat my body and make it my slave' (1 Cor. 9: 27).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e420a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e427" publication-type="other">
Bert Musschenga's (2004) study on 'integrity' distinguishes between coherence and
consistency: 'consistency' refers to a specific set of rules or a specific practice, while 'cohe-
rence' is reserved for the relation between such sets or practices. This is a useful distinction,
but not needed for our present purpose.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e444a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e451" publication-type="other">
The same point could have been illustrated with Oblomov, the protagonist of a novel by
Ivan Goncharov (1859), or the Fiddler in H.Chr. Anderson's Only a Fiddler (1837) (because of
this book Anderson was severely criticized by Kierkegaard for lacking a life-view).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e464a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e471" publication-type="other">
'He respected discipline, especially that of the sciences, but did not deny himself other
forms of discipline. The work he undertook can be regarded as a war of conquest;... he was
reconquering the ramifications of all its greater and lesser spiritual itineraries, reconquering a
map composed of human beings. The fascination of his work is comparable, I believe, to that
of a map.' (Canetti 1999, 693-694)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e490a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e497" publication-type="other">
So Iris Murdoch in opposition to Sartre says: '....when action involves choosing between
worlds, not moving in a world, loving and valuing which were once the rhythm of our lives,
become problems.' (quoted in Mitchell 1989, 12).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e510a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e517" publication-type="other">
This is how Hendrik Algra (1974, 19) concluded his contribution at a student confe-
rence: 'Ik las eens een gedicht over de schippers op de donkere zeeën, die veilig om
gevaarlijke verborgen kusten buigen, omdat zij de hoge sterren gehoorzamen. Zijn Gods
geboden niet als de hoge sterren, met een zilveren stift in kaart gebracht aan de nachtelijke
hemel, opdat de schipper niet verdwaalt op de donkere zee? Die sterren, ze stormen zelf
tegelijk langs verre banen, die in duizendenjaren worden gemeten.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e540a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e547" publication-type="other">
'Die "Weltbilder", welche durch "Ideen" geschaffen wurden, haben sehr oft als Wiechen-
steller die Bahneri bestimmt, in denen die Dynamik der Interessen das Handeln fortbewegte.'
(Weber 1922, 252). Obviously, Weber uses 'Weltbild' where we would prefer 'worldview'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e560a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e567" publication-type="other">
See Henk Aay on the geographer A. van Deursen (1891-1963): he held 'to the principle
that in a religious and ethical sense the earth is at the center of the universe in spite of its
physical insignificance' (Aay and Griffioen 1998, 107).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e581a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e588" publication-type="other">
As Mrs. Thatcher said in an interview: 'They're casting their problem on society. And, you
know, there is no such thing as society. There are individual men and women, and there are
families.' Quoted by Douglas Keay, Woman's (him, 31 October 1987, 8-10 (Source: Wikiquote,
slightly different in Kuiper2009, 13).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e604a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e611" publication-type="other">
Some exceptions are Kennedy (1995) and Bader (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e618a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e625" publication-type="other">
T. S. Eliot's Murder in the Cathedral (1935) on the unconnectedness of traditional life: 'We
try to keep our households in order;/ The merchant, shy and cautious, tries to compile a little
fortune,/ And the labourer bends to his piece of earth, earth-colour, his own colour,/
Preferring to pass unobserved.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e641a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e648" publication-type="other">
See the final article of the Confessio Belgica : 'and their cause — at present condemned as
heretical and evil by many judges and civil officers — will be acknowledged as the "cause of the
Son of God.'". Their cause' renders in the original hun zaak'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e661a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e668" publication-type="other">
Here I hesitate because 'human flourishing' can also be used to promote a diffuse, non-
focused life-style, one which prefers to keep options open.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e678a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e685" publication-type="other">
Cf. Plato, Apology, 38a: 'the unexamined life is not worth living'. Groethuysen (1980, 34)
states in a similar vein that there are only two types of humans: 'l'homme philosophique et
l'homme non philosophique'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e699a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e706" publication-type="other">
On 'deep subjectivity' see Poole (1972); Tu Weiming's (1989, 25) notion of the
'profound person' is partly inspired by Roger Poole.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e716a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e723" publication-type="other">
For a classic account of disillusionment among intellectuals, see Crossman (1949) ('six
famous men tell how they changed their minds about Communism').</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e733a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e740" publication-type="other">
A lucid text on the structure-direction distinction is Wolters (1985). Gordon Spykman
(1985, 39) implicitly uses the same distinction reflecting on Paul's identity: 'Thus Paul was still
the same "man". There is thus continuity in humanitas, but a sweeping turn-around from
deformitas to conformitas in the orientation of his life.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e756a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e763" publication-type="other">
Earlier Scruton (2005, 219) recounted his experience when teaching a course on music
at Boston University. A large number of his students came from Christian homes; their assent
to a new outlook only became tangible when he played for them songs like 'Losing my
religion': 'Its confused but poignant words engaged with sentiments that were all but universal
in adolescents who had come from small-town America to their cynical classes in sin.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e782a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e789" publication-type="other">
Windelband died before having developed a philosophical system; he is remembered
mainly as a historiographer of philosophy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e799a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e806" publication-type="other">
wissenschaftliche Philosophie als Weltanschauungslehre heiBt das Ziel der universa-
len Weltbetrachtung.', Rickert (1921, 28); cf. Krijnen (2001, 121-127).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e817a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e824" publication-type="other">
I don't mean to say that the argumentation is lacking. In fact, a sizeable part of the System
der Philosophies dedicated to these worldviews: see Rickert (1921, 348-412).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e834a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e841" publication-type="other">
These worldviews are labeled as non-theoretical because lacking self-reflection — which
makes clear that 'theoretical' (in an eminent sense) is taken to be synonymous to 'philoso-
phical'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e854a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e861" publication-type="other">
Rickert publicly took issue with Jaspers' position: see Krijnen (2001, 125).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e868a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e875" publication-type="other">
Goethe, Faust, vol. 1, 'Scene: In the study': 'Geschrieben steht: „Im Anfang war das
Wort!" Hier stock' ich schon! Wer hilft mir weiter fort?...Auf einmal seh' ich Rat/Und
schreibe getrost: Im Anfang war die Tat'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e888a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e895" publication-type="other">
Das, was man Tod nennt, kann mein Werk nicht abbrechen, denn mein Werk soli
vollendet werden.... Ich habe zugleich mit der Ubernehmung jener groCen Aufgabe die
Ewigkeit an mich gerissen. '(Rickert 1932, 527, quoting Fichte ).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e908a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e915" publication-type="other">
'Die letzte Wurzel der Weltanschauungen ist das Leben.' (Dilthey 1931, 78).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e923a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e930" publication-type="other">
'With the Zwecksetzung a worldview gets the Sfiitze needed to be effective (bildmd,
geslaltend, mformiermd)(Dilthey 1931,84, 98).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e940a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e947" publication-type="other">
Vaden House (1988) noted such a fallacy in Berger and Luckmann (1967).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e954a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e961" publication-type="other">
See the Diltheyan vein in which Peter Winch (1977, 103) states the purpose of a philoso-
phy of the social sciences:...the investigation of a human society, whose very nature is to
consist in different and competing ways of life, each offering a different account of the
intelligibility of things. To take an uncommitted view of such competing conceptions is
peculiarly the task of philosophy; it is not its business to award prizes to science, religion, or
anything else. It is not its business to advocate any Weltanschauung.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e984a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e991" publication-type="other">
On the notion of 'answer' that informs Schultz' approach: see Geertsema (1993), Buijs
(2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1001a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1008" publication-type="other">
Groethuysen considered im Anfang war die Tat as the quintessence of the bourgeois
worldview breaking through in 18Lh century France: 'Im Anfang war die Tat. Weltanschauung
in diesem Sinne ist immer zunâchst Weltschôpfung, Weltformung.' (Groethuysen 1927, viii;
omitted in the English edition of 1968)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1024a1310">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1031" publication-type="other">
From his comment on the title of the Festschrift for H. Evan Runner, Hearing and Doing:
'But, for all of our focus on doing, we have always also insisted that our active lives of
obedience to divine directives must be characterized by a coherence that can only be found by
understanding our obligations in the context of a "world-and-life-view". — This is, in turn, the
embodiment of a way of life that nurtures in us (...) a "steady, habitual determination" to be
certain kinds of persons.' (Mouw 2006, 6)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1055a1310">
            <label>47</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1062" publication-type="other">
See his essay 'Personnalisme' (on Emmanuel Mounier and his influence): Ricoeur (1955,
135-163).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1072a1310">
            <label>48</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1079" publication-type="other">
This is how I tend to approach the category of 'embedded' worldviews discussed in
section 2.3, as structures showing a vacancy, like the absentee ownership of a house.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1089a1310">
            <label>49</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1096" publication-type="other">
The author has kindly given permission to quote from this unpublished essay.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1103a1310">
            <label>50</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1110" publication-type="other">
'En toute chose il faut considérer la fin', Fables de la Fontaine, III, 5: 'Le renard et le
bouc'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1120a1310">
            <label>51</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1127" publication-type="other">
Calvin Seerveld (2005, 69): 'a turbulent, daring argument with God for better treatment
in our very short lives.... [T] ell me... about the outcome, the end of the affair of me.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1137a1310">
            <label>52</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1144" publication-type="other">
For a gripping account of such a highway to the grave, see Murakami (2000) on the
Japanese Aum sect responsible for the gas attack in the Tokyo subway, March 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1155a1310">
            <label>53</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1162" publication-type="other">
However, J.M. Keynes had something serious in mind when he coined this phrase: 'The
long run is a misleading guide to current affairs. In the long run we are all dead. Economists
set themselves too easy, too useless a task if in tempestuous seasons they can only tell us that
when the storm is past the ocean is flat again.' Harrod (1972, 402) quotes from Λ Tract on
Monetary Reform (1923).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1181a1310">
            <label>54</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1188" publication-type="other">
Michael Polanyi (1962, 291) has diagnosed this kind of excuse: 'All major interpretative
frameworks have an epicyclical structure which supplies a reserve of subsidiary explanations for
difficult situations.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1201a1310">
            <label>55</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1208" publication-type="other">
Girard (2008, 43-44) concludes : 'Notre culte de Nietzsche, c'est le triomphe non de la
santé mais de la maladie, non de la vérité mais du mensonge.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1218a1310">
            <label>56</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1225" publication-type="other">
Thjs was a)so true 0f 'verantwoordelijkheid' in the Dutch language: 'De oudst bekende
plaats is van 1782... Kort daarna wordt het woord als politieke enjuridische term... algemeen,
onder invloed van fr. responsabilité dat, hoewel in het ofr. niet geheel onbekend, toch pas als
benaming voor een van de groote principes van de Fransche Revolutie (1789) werkelijk zal
gaan leven.' Woordmihoek der Nederlandsche Taal, Vol. XIX, Den Haag: Nijhoff, 1982, 137</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1244a1310">
            <label>57</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1251" publication-type="other">
'Je nach der letzten Stellungnahme ist fur den einzelnen das eine der Teufel und das
andere der Gott, und der einzelne hat sich zu entscheiden, welches fur ihn der Gott und
welches der Teufel ist. ' (Weber 1994, 17)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1264a1310">
            <label>58</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1271" publication-type="other">
See for instance the first edition of the Encyclopedia Britannica (1771) on 'atheism': '...
but it is justly questioned whether any man seriously adopted such a principle. These
pretensions, therefore, must be founded on pride or affection.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1285a1310">
            <label>59</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1292" publication-type="other">
If 'worldview' is to be used at all in this connection then preferably in the singular as
David Hesselgrave (1978, 172-182) has done by speaking of 'the worldview of ancient China'.
Indeed, 'Confucius' worldview was grounded in the ultimate nature of things', that is to say, it
was not presented as a claim rooted in a personal conviction.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1308a1310">
            <label>60</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1315" publication-type="other">
'C'était la partie la moins philosophe et la moins sérieuse de leur vie; la plus philosophe
était de vivre simplement et tranquillement.' (Pensées 331)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1325a1310">
            <label>61</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1332" publication-type="other">
From West's Encyclopedia of American Law ( h trp://www.answers.com/topic/pub I ic-i η te rest).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1339a1310">
            <label>62</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1346" publication-type="other">
"That individuals should be ignorant of certain articles of faith," writes Bossuet, "I readily
admit; but the Church conceals nothing of what Jesus Christ has revealed; and that is why the
faithful who do not know certain individual articles nevertheless confess them all in general
when they say, Ί believe in the universal Church.'" (Groethuysen 1968, 9)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1362a1310">
            <label>63</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1369" publication-type="other">
I concur with Shah and Farr (2011) vs. Obama. First comes a quote from President
Obama, then their commentary: '"What our deliberative, pluralistic democracy demands is that
the religiously motivated translate their concerns into universal, rather than religion-specific,
values." Religious motivation is fine; just don't make your religious views the basis for public
policy. But democracy "demands" no such thing. Democracy is a system that adjudicates
contending claims.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1392a1310">
            <label>64</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1399" publication-type="other">
I follow Skillen (2001, 121-122) and Chaplin (2011, 171-176) in restricting the core
meaning of public' to things that are qualified as public-legal, as well as by assuming that these
are 'things' belonging to the inner sphere of the state.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1413a1310">
            <label>65</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1420" publication-type="other">
'Der Ohnmâchtige, dem der Machthaber ungeheuer stark erscheint, sieht nicht, wie
wichtig diesem eine vollzàhliche Unterwerfung aller ist.... und wird nie begreifen, was die
Kniebeuge des letzten, vergessenen, armseligen Untertans dem glânzenden Kônig bedeutet.
'(Canetti 1980, 333)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1436a1310">
            <label>66</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1443" publication-type="other">
As explained elsewhere, normally the channel through which this happens is the political
party (see Griffioen 1995, 150-1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1453a1310">
            <label>67</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1460" publication-type="other">
The exclusion of partisanship is so essential to the modern state that even Marx's
program of the abolishment of the state presupposed a state wherein this had been achieved
(McMurtry 1978, 119).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1473a1310">
            <label>68</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1480" publication-type="other">
Compare Ricoeur (1998, 108) reminiscing about his experience of totalitarianism: 'It is
first of all totalizing human relations by dissolving all other social ties; it is producing a mass-
humanity, such that it no longer obeys any organizing principle other than the state,
incarnated in the person of the Leader.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1496a1310">
            <label>69</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1503" publication-type="other">
'The seminal neo-Calvinist insight at stake here is that the authority of the state is
"universal" yet not "exhaustive" or "omnicompetent".... We might say that the scope of the
state's competence is extensive — it in principle can touch any area of society — but not
intensive — it may not compromise the irreducible, non-transferrable authority of a social
institution arising from its "sphere sovereignty".' (Chaplin 2004, 6)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1522a1310">
            <label>70</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1529" publication-type="other">
Compare John Gray (2000, 109): There are minimum standards of decency and
legitimacy that apply to all contemporary regimes, but they are not liberal values writ large.'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1540a1310">
            <label>71</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1547" publication-type="other">
I disagree with Ricoeur(1998, 105) proposing the notion of 'people of God' as 'a
resource for conceptualizing a political model', in the sense of 'wishing to live together as the
practice of fraternity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1560a1310">
            <label>72</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1567" publication-type="other">
Flannery O'Connor quoted in Mouw and Griffioen (1992, 89).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1198e1574a1310">
            <label>73</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1198e1581" publication-type="other">
Broad definitions are often used in Christian apologetics. One example: 'Everyone has a
worldview. Whether or not we realize it, we all have certain presuppositions and biases that
affect the way we view all of life and reality. A worldview is like a set of lenses which taint our
vision or alter the way we perceive the world around us.' (http://christianworldview.net/,
consulted Jan. 23, 2012)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1198e1609a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1613" publication-type="other">
Aay, Henk and Griffioen, Sander (eds.) (1998), Geography and Worldview,
Lanham (MD): University Press of America.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1623a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1627" publication-type="other">
Algra, Hendrik (1974), 'Wat is normaal?', in: Hendrik Algra, Bob Goudzwaard,
J.P.A. Mekkes, Wat is normaal?, Baarn: Bosch 8c Keuning.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1637a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1641" publication-type="other">
Bader, Veit (2007), Secularism or Democracy? Associational Governance of Religious
Diversity, Amsterdam: Amsterdam U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1651a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1655" publication-type="other">
Berger, Peter L. and Luckmann, Thomas (1967), The Social Construction of
Reality, New York: Anchor Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1666a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1670" publication-type="other">
Boffetti, Jason (2004), 'How Richard Rorty Found Religion', First Things, 123,
May 2004, 24-30. (http://www.flrstthings.com/ftissues/ft0405/articles/
boffetti)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1683a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1687" publication-type="other">
Buys, Govert (with P. Blokhuis, S. Griffioen and R. Kuiper) (2005), Homo
Respondens; Festschrift for Henk Geertsema, Amsterdam: Buijten en
Schipperheijn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1700a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1704" publication-type="other">
Canetti, Elias (1980), Masse und Macht. Frankfurt: Fischer. First published in
1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1714a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1718" publication-type="other">
Canetti, Elias (1999), The Memoirs of Elias Canetti, New York: Farrar, Straus &amp;
Giroux.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1728a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1732" publication-type="other">
Carrithers, Michael, Collins, Steven and Lukes, Steven (eds.) (1985), The Category
of the Person, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1742a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1746" publication-type="other">
Cather, Willa (1971), Death Comes for the Archbishop, New York: Vintage. First
published 1927.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1757a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1761" publication-type="other">
Chaplin, Jonathan (2004), 'Defining "Public Justice" in a Pluralistic Society', Pro
Rege XXXII (3), 1-11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1771a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1775" publication-type="other">
Chaplin, Jonathan (2011), Herman Dooyeweerd; Christian Philosopher of State and
Civil Society, Notre Dame: Notre Dame U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1785a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1789" publication-type="other">
Cherry, Conrad (1995), Hurrying toward Zion. Universities, Divinity Schools, and
American Protestantism, Bloomington: Indiana U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1799a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1803" publication-type="other">
Crossman, Richard (ed.) (1949), The God That Failed, A. Confession, New York:
Harper Bros.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1813a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1817" publication-type="other">
Cuddihy, John Murray (1974), The Ordeal of Civility: Marx, Lévi-Strauss, and the
Jewish Struggle with Modernity, Boston: Beacon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1827a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1831" publication-type="other">
Cuddihy, John Murray (1978), No Offense: Civil Religion and Protestant Taste, New
York: The Seabury Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1842a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1846" publication-type="other">
Dilthey, Wilhelm (1931 ), Gesammelte Schriften VIII, edited by B. Groethuysen,
Leipzig. First published in 1911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1856a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1860" publication-type="other">
Dooyeweerd, Herman (1953), A New Critique of Theoretical Thought, Volume 1,
Amsterdam/Philadelphia: Paris/ Presbyterian &amp; Reformed Publishing
Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1873a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1877" publication-type="other">
Ehrman,John (1969-1996), The Younger Pitt, three volumes, London: Constable.
Quoted as Ehrman 11969, Ehrman II1983, Ehrman III 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1887a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1891" publication-type="other">
Geertsema, Henk G. (1993), 'Homo Respondens. On the historical nature of
human reason', Philosophia Reformata 58, 120-152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1901a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1905" publication-type="other">
Girard, René (2008), 'Le sens de l'histoire'. Excerpts from a conversation with
Benoît Chantre, in: Traces du sacré, texts published by the Centre Pompidou
apropos the exhibition Traces du sacré, Paris, May-August 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1922" publication-type="other">
Girardot, Norman J. (2002), The Victorian Translation of China. James Legge's
Oriental Pilgrimage, Berkeley: University of California Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1933a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1937" publication-type="other">
Gousmettt, Chris (2011), 'Emergent Evolution, Augustine, Intelligent Design,
and Miracles', Philosophia Reformata 76, 119-137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1947a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1951" publication-type="other">
Graham, A.C. (1989), Disputers of the Tao. Philosophical Argument in Ancient China,
Chicago: Open Court.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1961a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1965" publication-type="other">
Gray, John (2000), Two Faces of Liberalism, Cambridge: Polity Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1972a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1976" publication-type="other">
Griffioen, Sander (1976), De Roos en het Kruis; De waardering van de eindigheid in
het latere denken van Hegel, Assen: Van Gorcum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e1986a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e1990" publication-type="other">
Griffioen, Sander (1995), 'The Relevance of Dooyeweerd's Theory of Institu-
tions', in S. Griffioen and B.M. Balk (eds.), Philosophy at the Close of the 20th
Century, Kampen: Kok.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2007" publication-type="other">
Griffioen, Sander (1998), 'Rickert, Windelband, Hegel und das Weltan-
schauungsbedurfnis', in Ch. Krijnen and E.W. Orth (eds.), Sinn, Geltung
Wer;. Neukantianische Motive in der modernen Kulturphilosophie, Wùrzburg:
Kônigshausen &amp; Neumann.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2024a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2028" publication-type="other">
Griffioen, Sander (2006), Een weggaan; Cultuurfilosofie tussen West en Oost, Budel:
Damon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2038a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2042" publication-type="other">
Griffioen, Sander (2008), 'Secularisme en secularisatie', Philosophia Reformata
73, 71-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2052a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2056" publication-type="other">
Groen, Johannes F. (1990), Justice without Consensus; A Critical Assessment of John
Rawls's Mediation between Kantian and Hegelian Political Theory, Amsterdam:
Vrije Universiteit Huisdrukkerij.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2073" publication-type="other">
Groen, Hans (Johannes) (1998), Identiteit als belofte; Over organisaties die een naam
hebben op te houden, Zoetermeer: Boekencentrum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2083a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2087" publication-type="other">
Groen van Prinsterer, G. (1847), Ongeloof en revolutie; Eene reeks van historische
voorlezingen, Leiden: S. en J. Luchtmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2097a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2101" publication-type="other">
Groethuysen, Bernard (1927), Die Entstehung der biirgerlichen Welt- und Lebens-
anschauungin Frankreich I, Tubingen: Niemeyer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2116" publication-type="other">
Groethuysen, Bernard (1968), The Bourgeois. Catholicism vs. Capitalism in Eight-
eenth Century France, London: The Cresset Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2126a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2130" publication-type="other">
Groethuysen Bernard (1980), Anthropologe philosophique, Paris: Gallimard. First
published in German, 1928-1930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2140a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2144" publication-type="other">
Hall, H. Fielding (1906), A People at School, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2155" publication-type="other">
Hare, John (1997), The Moral Gap. Kantian Ethics, Human Limits, and God's
Assistance, Oxford: Clarendon Paperbacks.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2165a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2169" publication-type="other">
Harrod, R.F. (1972), The Life of John Maynard Keynes, Harmondsworth: Penguin
Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2179a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2183" publication-type="other">
Heidegger, Martin (1972), Holzwege, Frankfurt a. Main: Klostermann (1st
edition, Frankfurt, 1950).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2194a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2198" publication-type="other">
Heine, Heinrich (1834), Zur Geschichte der Religion und Philosophie in Deutschland
(On the History of Religion and Philosophy in Germany), Feedbooks, www.feed
books.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2211a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2215" publication-type="other">
Hesselgrave, David J. (1978), Communicating Christ Cross-Culturally. An Intro-
duction to Missionary Communication, Grand Rapids: Zondervan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2225a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2229" publication-type="other">
Hollak, J.H.A. (1966), Van causa sui tot automatie, Inaugural lecture, Catholic
University Nijmegen, Hilversum: Paul Brand.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2239a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2243" publication-type="other">
Hordijk, J.C. (2001), De démocratie van het respect; Schoolstrijd, levensbeschouwing en
publiek debat, Delft: Eburon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2253a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2257" publication-type="other">
House, D. Vaden (1988), Without God or his Doubles; A Study in the Philosophy of
Richard Rorty, Doctoral dissertation VU University, Amsterdam, Edmonton:
Laser Image.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2270a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2274" publication-type="other">
Inwood, Michael (1999), A Heidegger Dictionary, Oxford: Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2282a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2286" publication-type="other">
Jaspers, Karl (1947), Von der Wahrheit, Mvinchen: Piper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2293a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2297" publication-type="other">
Jaspers, Karl (1960), Vernunft und Existenz, Miinchen: Piper 1960. (First pre-
sented as lectures at the University of Groningen, 1935.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2307a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2311" publication-type="other">
Keller, Timothy (2008), The Reason for God; Belief in an Age of Scepticism, London:
Hodder &amp; Stoughton.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2321a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2325" publication-type="other">
Kennedy, James (1995), Building New Babylon: Cultural Change in the Netherlands
during the 1960s, Doctoral dissertation University of Iowa. Translated as
Nieuw Babylon in aanbouw: Nederland in dejaren. zestig, Amsterdam: Boom.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2338a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2342" publication-type="other">
Klapwijk, Jacob (2008), Purpose in the Living World? Creation and Emergent
Evolution, Cambridge U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2352a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2356" publication-type="other">
Koestler, Arthur (1941), Darkness at Noon, New York: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2364a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2368" publication-type="other">
Kreiter, Erik (2007), Philosophie as Weltanschauung in Trendelenburg Dilthey and
Windelband, Doctoral dissertation VU University, Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2378a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2382" publication-type="other">
Krijnen, Christian (2001), Nachmetaphysischer Sinn; Eine Problemgeschichtliche und
systematische Studie zu den Prinzipien der Wertphilosophie Heinnch Rickerts,
Doctiral dissertation VU University, Amsterdam, Wûrzburg: Kônigshausen
&amp; Neumann.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2398a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2402" publication-type="other">
Kuiper, Roel (2009), Moreel kapitaal;. De verbindingskracht van de samenleving,
Amsterdam: Buijten en Schipperheijn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2412a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2416" publication-type="other">
Legge, James (1895), The Chinese Classics II; The Works of Mencius, Oxford:
Clarendon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2426a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2430" publication-type="other">
Lief, Jason (2010), 'Christian Practices as Counter Discourses: Foucault, Barth
and the Discourse of Higher Education', Pro RegeXXIX (September), 1-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2440a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2444" publication-type="other">
Luna, Christopher M. (2011), Reason is a Choice, available at christopherm
luna.com (posted April 20, 2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2459" publication-type="other">
Marshall, Paul A. (1989), Stained Glass: Worldvieivs and Social Science, edited by
Paul A. Marshall, Sander Griffioen and Richard J. Mouw, Lanham (MD):
University Press of America.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2472a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2476" publication-type="other">
Maclntyre, Alasdair (1988), Whosefustice? Which Rationality?, Notre Dame Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2483a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2487" publication-type="other">
McMurtry, John (1978), The Structure of Marx's World-View, Princeton: Princeton
U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2497a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2501" publication-type="other">
Mekkes, J.P.A. (1978), 'Méthodologie en Praxis', Philosophia Reformata 43, 3-10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2508a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2512" publication-type="other">
Mouw, Richard and Griffioen, Sander (1992), Pluralisms and Horizons, Grand
Rapids: Eerdmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2522a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2526" publication-type="other">
Mouw, Richard (2006), 'Virtue Ethics and the Public Calling of Reformational
Thought', Philosophia Reformata 71, 3-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2537a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2541" publication-type="other">
Murakami, Haruki (2000), Underground: The Tokyo Gas Attack and the Japanese
Psyche, translated by Alfred Birnbaum and Philip Gabriel, New York,
London: Vintage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2554a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2558" publication-type="other">
Musschenga, A.W. (2004); Integriteit; Eenheid en heelheid van de mens, Utrecht:
Lemma.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2568a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2572" publication-type="other">
Naugle, David K. (2002), Worldview. The History of a Concept, Grand Rapids:
Eerdmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2582a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2586" publication-type="other">
Nietzsche, Friedrich (1966), Friedrich Nietzsche Werke, edited by Karl Schlechta,
Volume III.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2596a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2600" publication-type="other">
Olthuis, James H. (1989), 'On Worldviews', in Marshall (1989).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2607a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2611" publication-type="other">
Polany, Karl (1958), Personal Knowledge, London: Routledge &amp; Kegan Paul.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2619a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2623" publication-type="other">
Poole, Roger (1972), Towards a Deep Subjectivity, New York: Harper &amp; Row.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2634" publication-type="other">
Rawls,John (1973), A Theory of Justice, Oxford: OUP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2641a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2645" publication-type="other">
Rawls, John (1993), Political Liberalism, New York: Columbia University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2652a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2656" publication-type="other">
Rickert, Heinrich (1921), AUgemeine Grundlegung der Philosophie, Tubingen:
Mohr.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2666a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2670" publication-type="other">
Rickert, Heinrich (1926), 'Max Weber und seine Stellung zur Wissenschaft',
Logos 152, 222-237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2680a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2684" publication-type="other">
Rickert, Heinrich (1932), Goethes Faus;. Die dramatische Einheit der Dichtung,
Tûbingen: Mohr.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2695a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2699" publication-type="other">
Ricoeur, Paul (1955), Histoire et vérité, Paris: Seuil.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2706a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2710" publication-type="other">
Ricoeur, Paul (1990), Soi-même comme un autre, Paris: Seuil.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2717a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2721" publication-type="other">
Ricoeur, Paul (1998), Critique and Conviction; Conversations with François Azouvi
and Marc de Launay, translated by Kathleen Blarney, New York: Columbia
U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2734a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2738" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, Heinrich (1931), Philosophisches Wdrterbuch, Leipzig: Kroner.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2749" publication-type="other">
Schultz, Gianfranco (2005), 'Homo Audiens. Wereldbeschouwing als ant-
woord', in Buijs (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2763" publication-type="other">
Scruton, Roger (2005), Gentle Regrets; Thoughts from a Life, London: Continuum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2771a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2775" publication-type="other">
Shah, Tim and Farr, Tom (2011), 'Religion in the Public Square', New York
Times, The Opinion Pages, Room for Debate, December 27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2785a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2789" publication-type="other">
Seerveld, Calvin (2005), Voicing God's Psalms, Grand Rapids: Eerdmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2796a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2800" publication-type="other">
Sibley, Laurence C. (2010), Review of James K.A. Smith, Desiring the Kingdom, Pro
RegeXXXVIII (4), 34-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2810a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2814" publication-type="other">
Sieg, Ulrich (1994), Aufstieg und Niedergang des Marburger Neukantianismus,
Wûrzburg: Kônigshausen &amp; Neumann.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2824a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2828" publication-type="other">
Sire, James (1997), The Universe Next Door: A Basic Worldview Catalo, 3rd edition,
Downers Grove: InterVarsity.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2838a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2842" publication-type="other">
Skillen, James (2001), 'Politics in One World', Philosophia Reformata 66, 117-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2850a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2854" publication-type="other">
SOED (2007), Shorter Oxford English Dictionary Sixth Edition (version 3.0.2.1),
Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2864a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2868" publication-type="other">
Smith, James K.A. (2009), Desiring the Kingdom. Worship, Worldview, and Cultural
Formation, Grand Rapids: Baker.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2878a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2882" publication-type="other">
Smith, James K.A. (2011), 'Worldview, Sphere Sovereignty, and Desiring the
Kingdom, Pro Rege XXXIX (4), 15-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2892a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2896" publication-type="other">
Spykman, Gordon J. (1985), Spectacles; Biblical Perspectives on Christian Scholarship,
Potchefstroom University for CHE: Potchefstroom.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2906a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2910" publication-type="other">
Taylor, Charles (2007), A Secular Age, Cambridge (Mass.): Belknap Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2917a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2921" publication-type="other">
Terrien, Samuel (2003), The Psalms; Stropliic Structure and Theological Commentary,
Grand Rapids: Eerdmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2936" publication-type="other">
Tu, Wei-ming (1989), Centrality and Commonality; An Essay on Confucian Religious-
ness, Albany: SUNY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2946a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2950" publication-type="other">
Vanderhorn, Cor (2009), Turning a Christian Worldview into an Educational
Framework, MA thesis International Master Christian Studies, VU University,
Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2963a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2967" publication-type="other">
Van der Walt, B.J. (2011), Flying on the Wings of Vollenhoven's Radical Christian
worldview; A [{reconsideration of the Usual Typology of Christian Worldviews,
Paper delivered at the Koers-75 Conference on "Worldview and educa-
tion", 31/05/2011-02/06/2011, Potchefstroom.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2983a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e2987" publication-type="other">
Van Dyke, Harry (1989), Groen van Prinsterer's Lectures on Unbelief and Revolution,
Jordan Station (Ont.): Wedge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e2997a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3001" publication-type="other">
Van Riessen, Hendrik (1967), Mondigheid en de machten, Amsterdam: Buijten &amp;
Schipperheijn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3011a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3015" publication-type="other">
Verhoogt, J.P., Griffioen, S. and Fernhout, R. (eds.) (1997), Vinden. en zoeken: het
bijzondere van de Vrije Universiteit, Kampen: Kok. Quoted as Verhoogt (1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3026a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3030" publication-type="other">
Weber, Max (1994), Wissenschaft als Beruf W.J. Mommsen. and W. Schluchter
(eds.), Studienausgabe der Max Weber-Gesamtausgabe Band 1/17, Tûbin-
gen: J.C.B. Mohr. (This lecture was delivered Winter 1917-8.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3043a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3047" publication-type="other">
Weber, Max (1922), Gesammelte Aufsâtze zur Religionssoziologie I, Tubingen: J.C.B.
Mohr.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3057a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3061" publication-type="other">
Winch, Peter (1977), The Idea of a Social Science and its Relation to Philosophy,
London: Routledge &amp; Kegan Paul. First edition 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3071a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3075" publication-type="other">
Wolters, Albert (1985), Creation Regained; Biblical Basics for a Reformational
Worldview, Grand Rapids: Eerdmans.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3085a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3089" publication-type="other">
Wolters, Albert M. (1989), 'The Idea of Worldview', in Marshall (1989).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3096a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3100" publication-type="other">
Wolterstorff, Nicholas (2008), Justice: Rights and Wrongs, Princeton: Princeton
U.P.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1198e3111a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1198e3115" publication-type="other">
Zuidema, S.U. (1972), Communication and Confrontation. A Philosophical Appraisal
and Critique of Modern Society and Contemporary Thought, Assen/Kampen: Van
Gorcum/Kok.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
