<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">strastudquar</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50020058</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Strategic Studies Quarterly</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Air University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19361815</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19361823</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26269787</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Perspectives</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>How Terrorist Groups End</article-title>
            <subtitle>Studies of the Twentieth Century</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Harmon</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Christopher C. Harmon taught strategy and policy at the Naval War College and held the Kim T. Adamson Chair of Insurgency and Terrorism (2005-2007) at the Command and Staff College, Marine Corps University. He is author of the graduate-level textbook, Terrorism Today, published by Frank Cass (2000) and Routledge (2007), and articles in such journals as Vital Speeches. From 2007 through 2010 he directed curricula for the George C. Marshall Center’s Program on Terrorism and Security Studies. This article, edited for length, is reprinted from his new book, Toward a Grand Strategy against Terrorism (McGraw-Hill, 2010).</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>FALL 2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26269783</issue-id>
         <fpage>43</fpage>
         <lpage>84</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26269787"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>Notes</title>
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <p>Scholars must recognize certain intellectual debts, and good scholars enjoy doing so. My debts are happily paid in this and earlier places, especially to Martha Crenshaw. One begins with her essay<mixed-citation publication-type="other">“How Terrorism Declines,” in Terrorism and Political Violence 3, no. 1 (Spring 1991): 69–87</mixed-citation>, and its admirable chart. There was a distinctive direction to my body of earlier work on this subject (e.g., many public presentations in 2004, a speech on Capitol Hill, a Webcast from the Woodrow Wilson Center in Washington, DC, on 20 March 2006, a book chapter with Cambridge University Press earlier that year, etc.). It was to retrace researches I’d made over a previous quarter century, present a half dozen leading reasons for terrorist group decline, and then detail examples within each rubric. The present essay’s approach is new, guided more by chronology, and my analysis profits from continued study of individual-named terror groups. Endnotes for chap. 7 of my book<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Terrorism Today, 2nd ed. (London &amp; New York: Routledge, 2007)</mixed-citation>indicate other resources I found worthy.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joseph T. McCann, Terrorism on American Soil: A Concise History of Plots and Perpetrators from the Famous to the Forgotten (Boulder, CO: Sentient Publications, 2006), 33–40</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Labor histories by L. Adamic and G. W. Meaker are cited in Walter Laqueur, The Age of Terrorism, 2d ed. (Boston: Little, Brown &amp; Co., 1987), 75</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barbara Tuchman, The Proud Tower: A Portrait of the World before the War, 1890–1914 (New York: Scribner/Macmillan, 1966).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <p>There are two good English-language accounts (known to me) of the precipitous fall of N17. A gifted student at the Institute of World Politics in Washington, DC, aviation security expert Mr. Paris Michaels, wrote an unpublished 2003 paper for our course. George Kassimeris of the University of Wolverhampton, England, published a detailed article,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Last Act in a Violent Drama? The Trial of Greece’s Revolutionary Organization 17 November,” Terrorism and Political Violence 18, no. 1 (March 2006): 137–57</mixed-citation>. The group’s head of operations is quoted saying the group was finished as a terrorist organization yet could return in some other form, “perhaps, in 10–15 years’ time, a new generation of fighters for the people might relaunch the struggle” (p. 153). It may be relevant that several Greek cities faced protracted rioting in late 2008 following a police shooting, and that since 2003 a terrorist group called Revolutionary Struggle has emerged.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <p>I have often spoken in lectures of the roles of Horst Herold and German police in the attrition of the RAF cadre. Introducing “computer profiling” and diligence with detail allowed federal authorities to find, one by one, the RAF militants. As there were never more than a few dozen weapons-carrying members; arrests reduced the group to nothing. In recent years, nearly all members have been released from jail. The unrepentant Hans Christian Klar, guilty of 20 murders or attempted murders, won early release in late 2008, prompting debate in Germany and this comment by Bavarian justice minister Joachim Hermann: “Klar deserves no sympathy as long as he continues to show none for his victims.”<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christian Science Monitor, 22 December 2008</mixed-citation>; and<mixed-citation publication-type="other">BBC News, 19 December 2008</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <p>This appellation, often self-applied by the terrorists, was taken up by two scholars as a subtitle for their fine book,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Europe’s Red Terrorists: The Fighting Communist Organizations, by Yonah Alexander and Dennis Pluchinsky (London: Frank Cass, 1992)</mixed-citation>. They include several post-1990 RAF documents, such as the aforementioned confession of failure dated 15 April 1992. In 1998 came yet another confession of failure from an RAF hand, so that year, too, appears in print sometimes as “the end of the Baader-Meinhof organization.”</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <p>One careful listing of relevant regional and subregional offices and organizations is by Florina Cristiana (Cris) Matei, “Combating Terrorism and Organized Crime: South EasternEurope Collective Approaches,” in Bilten Slovenske Vojske, the journal of the Slovenian Armed Forces (September 2008), 37–58.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <p>Teaching case studies of counterinsurgency success long ago convinced me that defections are a superior metric for decline. When Colombia’s vice-minister of defense Sergio Jaramillo wrote “Pourquot le Temps Joue Contre les FARC” for Le Figaro, 23 January 2008, he reported that 1,454 FARC members had quit in 2007, double of the previous year. As this occurred in the context of much-enhanced skills and professionalism by the Colombian armed forces, I took it to be highly significant. A few months later, the Ingrid Betancourt hostage party was rescued in a Colombian special forces operation—another case in which years of negotiations failed but surgical force worked brilliantly.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Turner Diaries, a 1978 novel by William L. Pierce</mixed-citation>(writing under the pseudonym Andrew MacDonald), is linked to at least five killings or nonlethal terrorist incidents of 1995–2006; see the 2d edition of my book<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Terrorism Today, 18–19. Other incidents in the present text are documented by Department of Justice/FBI publication Terrorism in the United States: 1999—30 years of Terrorism, A Special Retrospective Edition (Montgomery, AL: Southern Poverty Law Center Publications, 2001)</mixed-citation>and by media reports.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <p>This answer reveals the difference between “pro-state” terrorism and right-wing terrorism. The former is exercised by agents or partisans of state power, but in the US case it was precisely federal power that was most active against the racists. Right-wing terrorism of the KKK sort was by substate actors who hated the federal government’s intervention in southern American affairs.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <p>This also happened in Cologne, Germany. In September 2008, a few dozen rightists appeared to rally against “Islamisation and immigration invasion.” Forty thousand counterprotestors swamped the scene, and the initial marchers literally fled. See Jess Smee, “ ‘Anti-Islamisation’ Event Abandoned after Protests,”<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Irish Times, 20 September 2008, http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2008/0920/1221835126595.html</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Europol, EU Terrorism Situation and Trend Report, March 2007, www.europol.europa.eu</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <p>When freed from jail in the mid 1980s, Tupamaros leader Raul Sendic refounded his movement as a legitimate political party—the Movement of Popular Participation—and that, too, is part of how some terror groups end. On such groups as the Tupamaros, the best single source is<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michael Radu and Vladimir Tismaneanu, Latin American Revolutionaries: Groups, Goals, Methods (Washington: Pergamon-Brassey’s, 1990)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <p>One thorough English account of the chronicles of torture in Argentina is<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paul H. Lewis, Guerrillas and Generals: The “Dirty War” in Argentina (Westport, CT: Praeger, 2002), e.g., 150–59</mixed-citation>. The book was given to me by a gifted and humane military officer of that country who wished that others avoid his country’s mistakes while waging the “global war on terror.”</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paul Hockenos, Joschka Fisher and the Making of the Berlin Republic (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2007)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Claire Sterling, The Terror Network: The Secret War of International Terrorism (New York: Henry Holt &amp; Co., 1981), chap. 2</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <p>The impressive and deliberative way Italian democracy brought an end to terrorism has been remarkably understudied despite bales of publications on that country’s violence. A recent exception is the well-done Leonard Weinberg chapter, “The Red Brigades.” It does note that the antiterrorist police DIGOS probably used torture in a very few cases during the attempt to find kidnapped NATO general James Dozier and in its aftermath.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Democracy and Counterterrorism: Lessons from the Past, eds. Robert Art and Louise Richardson (Washington: US Institute of Peace Press, 2007), 49–56</mixed-citation>, are relevant.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <p>No Italian leftist killings of the 1980s (after 1981) make the 31-page chronicle of international terror incidents 1920–2007 by<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ann E. Robertson, Terrorism and Global Security (New York: Facts on File, 2007)</mixed-citation>. My main source is the detailed research in Donnatella della Porta, “Left Wing Terrorism in Italy,” in Terrorism in Context, ed. Martha Crenshaw (University Park: Pennsylvania State University Press, 1995). Certainly there have been leftist terrorist actions in Italy in the last 10 years; two murders in 2002 and 2003 were claimed by a group calling itself “Red Brigades,” prompting newspaper reports of a revival.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <p>I have yet to study Pierre Vallieres’ introduction to the movement,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qu’est-ce que le FLQ? but read with profit his 1967/1968 aggressively titled prison memoir White N------of America: The Precocious Autobiography of a Quebec “Terrorist” (New York: Monthly Review, 1968)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <p>One contribution to this Canadian case is<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ted Robert Gurr, “Terrorism in Democracies,” chap. 6, in Origins of Terrorism, a superb book edited by Walter Reich (Washington: Woodrow Wilson Center Press, 1998)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <p>It is not surprising that Filiberto Ojeda Rios declined to “walk away” from terrorism when discovered in September 2005 or that the FBI had to use its weapons. In a previous arrest, this same terrorist had begun burning documents when agents knocked at his door; he then opened fire with a machine gun, blinding an FBI agent in the eye. Ojeda Rios was disarmed. Later he jumped bail.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <p>If some four million live on the island of Puerto Rico, more than two million more now live in the rest of the United States—which helps explain the disparate locations of these terrorist attacks.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <p>See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Timeline: ETA Attacks,” BBC News, last updated 6 August 2009, http://news.bbc .co.uk/2/hi/europe/545452.stm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Paris and Madrid United against Terrorism,” Le Figaro, 11 January 2008 (trans. CCH).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <p>American writers, even in military journals, sometimes misrepresent Mao’s concepts. From his writings of the 1920s and 1930s and the historical work of Samuel Griffith, I see “phase one” warfare as the strategic defensive—characterized by political organization and guerrilla war (as well as terrorism, which Mao usually declines to mention). “Phase two” warfare is a strategic equilibrium in which the insurgency is strong enough to hold its ground, and in which guerrilla war continues, supplemented by positional and even conventional war elements. In “phase three,” the insurgency has developed well politically and is battle-tested militarily, and commanders can use all manners of fighting that are appropriate, especially conventional positional war. Mao’s theory is too often treated skeptically, even by scholars; it well accounts for the progress and successful resolution of wars in China (1949) and Vietnam (1975). The FARC and LTTE are thus groups that for many years have been locked into “phase two” war with their respective enemies. For an effective use of Mao’s theory to illuminate modern Islamist fighting, see<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dr. Norman Cigar’s introduction to Abd al-Aziz al-Muqrin, A Practical Course for Guerrilla War: Al Qaida’s Doctrine for Insurgency (Dulles, VA: Potomac Books, 2008)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <p>One Sikh group took down an Air Canada flight, killing 329 passengers, in June 1985. Perhaps a scholar interested in how terror groups end, a regional expert such as K. P. S. Gill, will one day detail how it was that international Sikh terror had so short a lifespan.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ami Pedahzur, William Eubank, and Leonard Weinberg, “The War on Terrorism and the Decline of Terrorist Group Formation: A Research Note,” Terrorism and Political Violence 14, no. 3 (Autumn 2002): 141–47</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <p>Of the several English-language books on Aum, the best may be Ian Reader,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Religious Violence in Contemporary Japan: The Case of Aum Shinrikyo (Richmond, UK: Curzon, 2000), e.g., 193–95</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haruki Murakami, trans. A. Birnbaum and P. Gabriel, Underground: The Tokyo Gas Attack and the Japanese Psyche (New York: Vintage Books, 2001)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David E. Kaplan and Andrew Marshall, The Cult at the End of the World: The Terrifying Story of the Aum Doomsday Cult, from the Subways of Tokyo to the Nuclear Arsenals of Russia (New York: Crown Publishers, 1996), 108–12</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <p>Lt Col John Kane, USMC, has been of good help in tracking the cyber side of Aum and of Aleph.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <p>While events in 2008 seemed to instruct the national government in the dangers Hezbollah poses inside Lebanon, it has been striking to hear how apologetic many previous official statements have been. Twice I heard radio interviews in which the Lebanese ambassador to the United States said nothing but good about Hezbollah and blamed the group’s violence on the “Israeli occupation”—which, with the exception of a couple of farms, had ended years before. Government spokesmen were ignoring as well the policy ends of Hezbollah, which are contrary to those of democratic, multiconfessional Lebanon, and the meddling of Iran, which Hezbollah itself counts as its mentor.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <p>According to A. N. Pratt, posted to a Middle East diplomatic mission during early 2008, Iran gives HAMAS some $120 million a year. Other estimates of Iranian aid to Hezbollah have been as high.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <p>See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Department of State, Country Reports on Terrorism—2007 (Washington: Government Printing Office, April 2008)</mixed-citation>, and past versions of this State Department annual, which has appeared for three decades. In certain recent years the report suffered from flaws in its statistics, which required correction in some cases, but I do not accept the implications suggested by resultant newspaper articles. I find the report in general an admirable compilation and a sound record of most events, highly useful to scholars, and less flawed than the terrorism coverage of many books and periodicals.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <p>“The Covenant of the Islamic Resistance Movement,” offered up to the “Name of the Most Merciful Allah,” is dated 18 August 1988 and may be found on the website of the Avalon Project at Yale Law School, http://avalon.law.yale.edu/subject_menus/mideast.asp.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <p>When speaking of a group’s lifespan, I refer to its participation in violence of consequence to the state; therefore, some periods of several years or even a decade (e.g., Sendero in the 1970s) spent in preparation and planning may be excluded. So, too, might one exclude years of quiet after violence (as when members of the Symbionese Liberation Army, having failed, hid underground, 1976–1999). My chart shows dates for the group’s existence, but others for the years of “main violence.” Consistent with the PTSS approach, I include discussion of appropriate insurgent groups that systematically employ terror; this article is not merely focused on small terrorist cells.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peter Janke, Guerrilla and Terrorist Organizations: A World Directory and Bibliography (New York: Simon &amp; Schuster, 1983), 23</mixed-citation>. The Hoffman group is so lost to history that even the US National Counterterrorism Center’s annual desk diaries say nothing of the bombing on 26 September 1980. Yet, its significance recurred in 2009 when the famous fall festival in Munich was again directly threatened by terrorists—of al-Qaeda.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Radu and Tismaneanu, Latin American Revolutionaries, 115–23</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <p>Ibid.; and<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Janke, Guerrilla and Terrorist Organizations, 431–40</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yonah Alexander and Dennis Pluchinsky, Europe’s Red Terrorists: The Fighting Communist Organizations (London: Frank Cass, 1992), 148–50</mixed-citation>. Marine Corps University was honored to have both these scholars in its colloquium on “Terrorist Group Vulnerabilities” in Quantico, VA, 30 April 2007.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <p>Are the Black Panthers a case of limited success? They emerged in 1966 and 1967 with aspirations to be a sort of armed wing of the civil rights movement. They expected status as a virtuous self-defense force and carried weapons openly amidst claims to protect their communities and their race from the diffidence of a white majority and the aggressions of its white government. Their quotidian work included “survival activities” such as providing food and medical aid and schools in impoverished areas. Their other side was to be found in brutalizing critics, open calls to “Kill the Pigs” (police), and physical attacks on the establishment. The Panthers found themselves very much out-gunned by police; many died at police hands, and their supporters often claimed assassination. More (including “defense minister” Huey Newton) died committing crimes or in battles with other black militants. Dozens were arrested and jailed for rape, drug-dealing, assault, and other crimes, illustrating the criminality often typical of a political terror group. A few Panther notables fled abroad, to return years later, usually disillusioned by life in Cuba or Algeria. Their organized political violence lasted but a half decade, ending in 1971/1972. Some Panthers spent the next years folding peaceably into American political and social life, winning community and city elections, or devoting themselves to education. Some wrote memoirs. They had not fallen into indiscriminate killing of normal citizens; this set them apart and helped make them a limited success in America. Panthers would doubtless claim to have helped the civil rights movement by using publicity, psychological shock, and the spectacle of openly bearing arms; they would say they advanced with force while other black activists advanced related causes in more pacific, less controversial ways. There are many published memoires on these times—some by Panthers themselves—as well as<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peter Collier and David Horowitz, Destructive Generation: Second Thoughts about the ’60s (New York: Summit Books, 1990), 149 ff; and Crenshaw, “How Terrorism Declines,” 81</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <p>Dr. David Tucker is one of the very few American authors in recent years to document and discuss Castroite terrorism during the rise to power, which ended in 1959—something older reports and US congressional hearings used to cover. Tucker details several incidents of hostage taking and so forth in a book drawing well on both his DoD and academic work,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skirmishes at the Edge of Empire: The United States and International Terrorism (Westport, CT: Praeger, 1997)</mixed-citation>. My point that guerrilla war was far more important than terrorism is also why this essay does not attempt to include so massive a movement as the Chinese Communist Party’s rise to state power in 1949.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <p>One notable Huk attack devastated a military hospital and featured widespread murder of patients. That is a tactic even the most nihilistic terrorist groups avoid—although certain Chechens savaged a hospital.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <p>By contrast, Malaysian communists were pushed out without surrendering. Chin Peng and some remnants held out for decades in Thai border areas, quitting only with a treaty signed 2 December 1989.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <p>The Tupamaros became fashionable; their kidnapping and political theater tactics excited widespread admiration on the militant left. One testament to this is Russell Little’s words in a documentary film about his group, the Symbionese Liberation Army (SLA) of California. He discusses their fascination with the group and the film “State of Siege” (“État de Siège”) and says his own SLA literally took form from a discussion group on political films running in Berkeley.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Stone’s “Guerrilla: The Taking of Patty Hearst” (Magnolia Pictures, 2005)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seth G. Jones and Martin C. Libicki, How Terrorist Groups End: Lessons for Countering al Qa’ida (Santa Monica, CA: RAND, 2008), chap. 4</mixed-citation>, “Politics and the FMLN in El Salvador.” The notion that this Cuban-organized group of communists and self-proclaimed armed forces was mainly pushing for “reforms” and “for the transition to a democratic political regime” is comically naïve (ibid., 64). After its defeats at phase-two-style fighting and disarmament under various national and international pressures, the FMLN did morph into a political party and compete in elections, often with a measure of success. A similar error occurs in table A.1 in which the “goal” of the 2nd of June Movement in Germany is declared to be “policy change.” They were anarchists, and later some joined the communist RAF.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phil Peters (Lexington Institute, Arlington, VA), interview by author, 2006</mixed-citation>. Peters worked on Central American issues for many years in the office of Rep. James A. Courter (R-NJ) on the House Armed Services Committee, where I also had the honor of employment.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donatella della Porta, “Left-Wing Terrorism in Italy,” in Terrorism in Context, ed. Martha Crenshaw (University Park: Pennsylvania State University Press, 1995), 121</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <p>See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richard Drake, The Aldo Moro Murder Case (Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1995), 259, ff.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <p>See, for example,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frank Hyland, “Peru’s Sendero Luminoso: From Maoism to Narco-Terrorism,” Jamestown Foundation Terrorism Monitor 6, no. 23 (8 December 2008), http://www.jamestown.org/programs/gta/single/?tx_ttnews[tt_news]=34237&amp;tx_ttnews[backPid]=167&amp;no _cache=1</mixed-citation>. The article states that “SL’s apparent resurgence may be viewed fairly as an integral part of a burgeoning wave of leftist ideology in Latin America . . . Concern over an SL comeback is well founded.” I think these reports are overblown. As a November 2009 briefing at the Marshall Center by a Peruvian lieutenant colonel indicates, the actual area of operations of Sendero today is miniscule and very isolated.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Janke, Guerrilla and Terrorist Organizations, 7–10</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Menachem Begin, trans. Samuel Katz, The Revolt: Story of the Ergun, 5th ed. (Jerusalem: Steimatzky, 1972); and Doris Katz, The Lady was a Terrorist: During Israel’s War of Liberation (New York: Shiloni Publishers, 1953)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Janke, Guerrilla and Terrorist Organizations, 245–47; and the Jewish Virtual Library, http://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <p>Lord Moyne was a friend of Winston Churchill. After the 1944 murder, the prime minister made a scorching speech in the House of Commons, describing Jewish “terrorism” as evil and risking comparison to acts by Nazi terrorists. This was a principled political posture, the right one, however difficult it must have been for Churchill, well known to be a friend to the Jews since his earliest years in parliament.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <p>There have been innumerable terrorist attacks upon those who would ameliorate social and economic problems, and often this is a strategy by the violent. Some of these are a pattern of anti–United Nations terrorism—e.g., today’s visible al-Qaeda hatreds of the United Nations. I have written on other such attacks in “The Assault on Aid Workers: A New Pattern in Terrorism,” Security Insights (January 2008), the first of a new series of policy papers from the Marshall Center.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <p>Authorities date the origin of the FMLN differently—1958, 1960, 1961, etc.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <p>A more common date of origin for the Tigers is 1976. This author chooses to begin when Velupillai Prabhakaran founded the Tamil New Tigers, 1972. An active terrorist and guerrilla in the next years, he refounded the Tigers as the LTTE in 1976.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <p>N17 prospered so long that some began to whisper that the socialist governments of Greece did not care to arrest the terrorists, given the targets they were choosing. Keith Weston, once part of an official British contingent in Greece, disagrees. He believes the extremely small size of the group and the blood connections many had as well ensured secrecy.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <p>The Kurdish PKK, the most beguiling of cases, may or may not deserve a place here in section III A. Once easily classified, this protracted insurgency has become an analytical challenge. Founded by Abdullah Ocalan in the mid 1970s and ruled continuously by this charismatic leader, it was decapitated in February 1999 with his arrest and rendition. Kurdish violence all but disappeared for some four years. Ocalan’s announcements from jail appeared to dissuade loyalists from terrorism, and no clear successor has appeared. The PKK appeared defeated. Then a shadow came over Turkey’s accomplishment; violence by Kurdish militants of unclear loyalty slowly reappeared. The leader’s son is an active militant, and new organizations that may or may not be well linked to the old have appeared and are fighting—in Turkey and from Iraq. There is, for example, the Kurdish Freedom Falcons, which the US State Department initially reported on neutrally and years later began referring to as a militant wing of the PKK. Today one must speak of a phoenix of Kurdish militancy. The US State Department and the government of Turkey see a new chapter in a long PKK life. Either of these different views may be defensible; a historian might well prefer the latter.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <p>Ken Duncan, the Marshall Center’s Program on Terrorism and Security Studies (PTSS) expert on Middle Eastern states’ sponsorship of terrorism, adds that Syria has been successful—a contrast with Libya.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jack Holland, The American Connection: US Guns, Money, and Influence in Northern Ireland (New York: Viking, 1987)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <p>This unique term preservationist is from Bard O’Neill. The term pro-state terrorist is inferior because it is less exact; some right-wing groups want to preserve the cultural or political status quo, not necessarily the sitting government, with whose police they often quarrel.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <p>Stephen Morris, an Australian scholar and former colleague at the Naval War College, propounded a very useful scheme for beginning study of an insurgent group—analyzing its performance in the overt political, the covert political, and the military realms. If we group terrorist violence in with the third category, the approach has much value for study of organizations such as Hezbollah and HAMAS, and to lesser degrees al-Qaeda.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <p>The second source, described as more careful, is the aforementioned Jones/Libicki study dated 2008, which declares on page xiv, “No religious group that has ended achieved victory since 1968.” A student of history inclined to think terrorism fails will be most content with the views of and best instructed in studying the works of Walter Laqueur. His decades of fine work, based on many primary sources and varied languages, have set high standards for writing the history of terrorism.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <p>The Abu Nidal Organization flourished for a quarter century and killed some 900 people before expiring from combined causes. These culminated in the shooting of the leader in Iraq but included internecine violence in the ANO, repudiation by other Palestinians, and a clever US effort in counterterrorism thus far described by almost no one in print; see the chapter on “History” in Tucker, Skirmishes at the Edge of Empire.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <p>ABC Radio News on 24 January 2009 named a released terrorist who rejoined al-Qaeda. These incidents have occurred perhaps once a year, during the very same years of popular European and American agitation for closure of the detention facility at Guantanamo Bay, on US–controlled land in Cuba.</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
