<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">enviphil</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016367</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Environmental Philosophy</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Philosophy Documentation Center</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">17180198</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21538905</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167140</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Features</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Soft Side of Stone</article-title>
            <subtitle>Notes for a Phenomenology of Stone</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Berleant</surname>
                  <given-names>Arnold</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>P. O. Box 52, Castine, ME USA 04421</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>Spring/Fall 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1 &amp; 2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167134</issue-id>
         <fpage>49</fpage>
         <lpage>58</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2007 The International Association for Environmental Philosophy</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167140"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Stone represents the firmness and intransigence of the world within which we live and act. But beyond the perception and appropriations of stone, diverse meanings lie hidden between the hardness of stone and its uses. At the same time meaning must be grounded in the stabilizing presence of a common world. Yet if all that can be said is not about stone simpliciter but only an aesthetics of its perception, uses, and meanings, have we not gained the whole world but lost its reality? The underlying issue is therefore not aesthetic but ontological.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Thoughts on an Aesthetics of Stone," University of Joensuu, Joensuu, Finland, January 20, 2005.</mixed-citation>An earlier, briefer version of this<mixed-citation publication-type="other">paper was first presented at the Conference on the Aesthetics of Stone and Rock, 14 June 2007, Koli, Finland.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <p>The complementary theory of catastrophism has been revived also.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <p>I am grateful to Riva Berleant for observing that old glacial ice is actually a changed substance and can be thought of as metamorphic rock.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tam Lin Neville, "Early Mornings," American Poetry Review 35/6 (November/December 2006): 33.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <p>Noguchi's UNESCO garden in Paris, Billy Rose's Sculpture Garden in Jerusalem, and his California Scenario.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <p>Andy Goldsworthy even gives stone biological properties when he says that the process of putting one stone on another is akin to the process of growth.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <p>"After we came out of the church, we stood talking for some time together of Bishop Berkeley's ingenious sophistry to prove the nonexistence of matter, and that every thing in the universe is merely ideal. I observed, that though we are satisfied his doctrine is not true, it is impossible to refute it. I never shall forget the alacrity with which Johnson answered, striking his foot with mighty force against a large stone, till he rebounded from it—'I refute it thus'" (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">James Boswell, The Life of Samuel Johnson [New York: Penguin Classics, 1979], Part 2, Ch. 13</mixed-citation>).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murakami Haruki, "The Kidney-Shaped Stone That Moves Everyday," The New Yorker, September 26, 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Bible, Psalm 18.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Dripping water hollows a stone." Lucretius, De Rerum Natura, Bk. I, 1. 313.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <p>"[P]ossession of linguistic color categories facilitates recognition and influences perceptual judgements, even in a language whose terms are less abstract than English."<mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Roberson, I. Davies, &amp; J. Davidoff, "Color categories are not universal: replications and new evidence from a Stone-Age culture," Journal of Experimental Psychology: General 129, no. 3 (2000): 369-398.</mixed-citation>Much research has supported the hypothesis that the categories of the language we use influence the way we perceive the world. Among the ways in which culture influences perception are by addition, omission, organization, sharpening, transformation.</p>
            <p>Carl Ratner cites the seminal work of Sapir, Whorf, Vygotsky, and Luria, all of whom maintained that "sensory processes are subordinated to and subsumed within 'higher' social psychological functions." He argues that not only are color boundaries and focal points socially mediated but psychological functions are, in general. See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carl Ratner, "A Sociohistorical Critique of Naturalistic Theories of Color Perception," Journal of Mind and Behavior 10 (1989): 361.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>See also<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Don Dedrick, Naming the Rainbow: Colour Language, Colour Science, and Culture (Dordrecht: Kluwer, 1998)</mixed-citation>, a history of studies of color terminology, both universalist and relativist, and theories in anthropology, linguistics, psychology, etc. The author takes a modified universalist view that a basic biological color perception exists in all human groups, with divergent cultural emphases. However, the question is not settled.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenneth Koch, "On Aesthetics," in One Train (New York: Knopf, 1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <p>Is this a philosophical parallel to the theological admonition, "What shall it profit a man if he gains the whole world and loses his own soul?" (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matthew 16:26</mixed-citation>).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <p>The full text is as follows: "I would fain ask those philosophers, who found so much of their reasonings on the distinction of substance and accident, and imagine we have clear ideas of each, whether the idea of substance be derived from the impressions of sensation or of reflection? If it be conveyed to us by our senses, I ask, which of them; and after what manner? If it be perceived by the eyes, it must be a colour; if by the ears, a sound; if by the palate, a taste; and so of the other senses. But I believe none will assert, that substance is either a colour, or sound, or a taste.</p>
            <p>The idea, of substance must therefore be derived from an impression of reflection, if it really exist. But the impressions of reflection resolve themselves into our passions and emotions: none of which can possibly represent a substance. We have therefore no idea of substance, distinct from that of a collection of particular qualities, nor have we any other meaning when we either talk or reason concerning it. The idea of a substance as well as that of a mode, is nothing but a collection of Simple ideas, that are united by the imagination, and have a particular name assigned them, by which we are able to recall, either to ourselves or others, that collection. But the difference betwixt these ideas consists in this, that the particular qualities, which form a substance, are commonly referred to an unknown something, in which they are supposed to inhere; or granting this fiction should not take place, are at least supposed to be closely and inseparably connected by the relations of contiguity and causation. The effect of this is, that whatever new simple quality we discover to have the same connexion with the rest, we immediately comprehend it among them, even though it did not enter into the first conception of the substance" (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Hume, Treatise of Human Nature, Bk. I, Part I, Sect. VI</mixed-citation>).</p>
            <p>Other relevant texts by Hume include the following:</p>
            <p>"Where then is the power, of which we pretend to be conscious? Is there not here, either in a spiritual or material substance, or both, some secret mechanism or structure of parts, upon which the effect depends, and which, being entirely unknown to us, renders the power or energy of the will equally unknown and incomprehensible?" (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Hume, An Enquiry Concerning Human Understanding, Section VII, Pt. I</mixed-citation>).</p>
            <p>"Thus neither by considering the first origin of ideas, nor by means of a definition are we able to arrive at any satisfactory notion of substance; which seems to me a sufficient reason for abandoning utterly that dispute concerning the materiality and immateriality of the soul, and makes me absolutely condemn even the question itself. We have no perfect idea of any thing but of a perception. A substance is entirely different from a perception. We have, therefore, no idea of a substance" (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Treatise of Human Nature, Bk. I, Part IV, Sect. V</mixed-citation>).</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
