<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">hebrewstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50001076</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Hebrew Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Association of Professors of Hebrew</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01464094</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26304277</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>“A STORY OR A BULLET BETWEEN THE EYES” ETGAR KERET</article-title>
            <subtitle>REPETITIVENESS, MORALITY, AND POSTMODERNISM</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schwartz</surname>
                  <given-names>Yigal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ben-Gurion University of the Negev</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">58</volume>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26304255</issue-id>
         <fpage>425</fpage>
         <lpage>444</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26304277"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The central strategy in Etgar Keret’s entire body of work is the combination of and the confrontation between two poetic moves: the looping repetition of narrative scenes, which seems mechanical, and the sudden appearance of an unusual conscious event, which disrupts the mechanism of repetition. The looping repetition is perceived here as a “narrative epidemic” that is hostile to any individual human performance. The appearance of the unusual event, which is seen here as a “narrative mutation,” creates a caesura in which a humanistic existential space, whose realization is a task imposed on the “right readers,” exists for an instant. These “right readers” must recognize this caesura, mark it, and then enlarge and expand it, and by doing so halt the looping movement and create a moral space, if only for a brief moment.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <p>Many critics and researchers have presented him as a representative of a generation and/or a period in the history of Israeli society. See, among others:<mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, המרד השפוף: על תרבות צעירה בישראל (A dispirited rebellion: Essays on contemporary Israeli culture; Tel Aviv: Hakibbutz Hameuchad, 1997), pp. 9–21, 137–147</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “ השואה בספרות העברית של הדור הצעיר ” (The Holocaust in the Hebrew literature of the younger generation), Tzafon 7 (1995): 151–169</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Peleg, Israeli Culture between the Two Intifadas: A Brief Romance (Austin: University of Texas Press, 2008), pp. 65–66</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nissim Calderon refers in his article “ ניגשים אל קו המים ” (Approaching the watershed), published in Yedioth Achronot on June 23, 1999 (p. 27)</mixed-citation>, to Keret’s great popularity among young people and the significance of this phenomenon. In another article, “ בלי פואנטה ” (No point), published in<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maariv on July 19, 2002 (p. 27)</mixed-citation>, he argues, among other things, that Keret has become a cultural hero because he promised readers that there was no lofty culture from which literature began.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Mendelson-Maoz, “ אתגר קרת ” (Etgar Keret), in לקסיקון הקשרים לסופרים ישר אלים (The Heksherim lexicon of Israeli authors; ed. Z. Stav and Y. Schwartz; Or Yehuda: The Heksherim Institute for the Study of Jewish and Israeli Literature and Culture, 2014), pp. 826–828</mixed-citation>.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Hefetz, “ ”רק הגיל צעיר (Only the age is young), Yedioth Achronoth (March 6, 1992)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <p>The fact that Keret is a multi-talented artist in several fields is connected, I believe, to an important principle of his artistic worldview: free movement between ontological, epistemological, imagined, and poetic worlds. This principle is connected in his eyes to having more than one identity. This is apparent, for example, in comments he made in a lecture at Ben-Gurion University on the work of one of his favorite authors, Kurt Vonnegut: “As a writer, Vonnegut crossed lines all the time and had more than one identity.” Keret’s closeness to Vonnegut probably also stems from their attraction to genres that are not considered serious. Vonnegut, Keret said in his lecture, “is considered a serious and important writer, but ‘sinned’ by writing satire and science fiction. In some of his books, he inserts especially childish illustrations and drawings.” Keret added that “in the eyes of many scholars, the fact that Vonnegut did not maintain a strictly serious image damaged his institutional reception.” (From Etgar Keret, manuscript). See also<mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Gurevich, 20- פוסטמודרניזם, תרבות וספרות בסוף המאה ה (Postmodernism, culture, and literature at the end of the twentieth century; Tel Aviv: Dvir, 1997), pp. 287–304</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Chodnovsky, האם קיימים חורים שחורים: על פרודיה בסיפורים קצרים של אורלי קסטל-בלום ואתגר קרת“ ” (Do black holes exist? On parody in the short stories of Orly Castel-Bloom and Etgar Keret), Iton 77 222–223 (1998): 24–29</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">I. Tzivoni, “ כי מקומיקס באת ואל קומיקס תשוב: כמה הערות על ספרות הקומיקס של אתגר קרת ” (Some comments on the comics literature of Etgar Keret), Iton 77 234–235 (1999): 26–24, 45</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <p>See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, pp. 9–21, 47–137</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Calderon, “Approaching the Watershed,” p. 27</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Calderon, “No Point,” p. 27</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <p>This is the place to note that starting at the end of the first decade of the twenty-first century, the voices of critics who attempted to reassess Keret’s work began to be heard. Some critics argued that Keret was repetitive, that he was recycling one trick, that he was basically a “copywriter author,” and so on and so forth. Others pointed out precisely the trends of change and development in his work. The first group of critics includes A. Glasner, “ אני כולה סתם גאון: ביקורת על ׳פתאום דפיקה בדלת׳ ”<mixed-citation publication-type="other">(Review of E. Keret, Suddenly, A Knock on the Door</mixed-citation>). NRG May 15, 2010. Online: http://www.nrg.co.il/online /47/ART2/106/301.html; R. Yagil, “ פתאום דפיקה במוח: על החדש של אתגר קרת ” (Suddenly, a knock on the brain: On Etgar Keret’s newest). NRG June 6, 2010. Online: http://www.nrg.co.il/online/47/ART2/106/301.html; and B. Ziffer “ לא פלא שבאירופה קונים את הבלוף המכונה ׳אתגר קרת׳ ” (If a German writer wrote like Etgar Keret, he would be booted out of town). Haaretz September 17, 2015. Oneline: http://www.haaretz.com /israel-news/.premium-1.676390. The second group includes O. Herzog, ׳פתאום דפיקה בדלת׳ מאת אתגר קרת: אנחנו כאן אורחים לרגע“ ” (Suddenly, a Knock on the Door by Etgar Keret: We are guests here for a moment). Haaretz, June 2, 2010;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. A. Shoshan, “ ”הייאוש, בנאדם(Despair, man). Haaretz, May 21, 2010; Y. Schwartz, “ ניסיון לאתר את מנגנון הפעולה של סיפורי אתגר קרת ” (An attempt to identify the mechanism of action in the stories of Etgar Keret). Haaretz, September 25, 2015</mixed-citation>, and others.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <p>For example,<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Orian, “ ליצנות מרירה, אופטימיזם מחויך ” (Bitter clowning and smiling optimism). Yedioth Achronoth, May 6, 1994</mixed-citation>.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Shklovsky, “ האושר הוא רגע גנוב וחולף ” (Happiness is a stolen, passing moment), Iton 77 268 (2002): 6</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “The Holocaust,” pp. 151–169</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y Orian, “Bitter Clowning”; F. Hefetz, “Only the Age is Young”; E. Avrahami, “ הרבה בקרובים והסרט איננו ” (Many trailers, no movie), Maariv, June 22, 1994</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Schwartz, “ ”הפוך על הפוך (Upside-down logic), Haaretz Books, May 14, 1997, pp. 6, 13</mixed-citation>.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">I. Tzivoni, “Some Comments,” pp. 24– 26, 45</mixed-citation>; and others. Yaron Peleg justifiably makes a connection between Keret’s meteoric reception and the fact that he integrated well with the rise of postmodernism in Israel. See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Peleg, Israeli Culture, pp. 65–66</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, p. 13</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, p. 13</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, p. 15</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, p. 15</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Taub, A Dispirited Rebellion, p. 15</mixed-citation>. I believe that Taub is mistaken in every one of the claims that compose this sequence, and I will elaborate upon this below. By the way, some of his errors stem from the supposedly clear and obvious labelling of Keret as belonging to the group of Israeli authors whose first books were published at around the same time as Pipelines, among them Uzi Weill, Gafi Amir, and others. However, actually, from a biographical point of view as well (mainly the fact that Keret is a member of the second generation after the Holocaust), and (and these things are interdependent on one another) from a poetic point of view, there is a connection between him and the group of authors I have called the “Yom Kippur Generation” (David Grossman, Itamar Levy, Lily Perry, Amnon Navot, and others), for whom “childishness” is a significant characteristic. See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Schwartz, מה שרואים מכאן: סוגיות בהיסטוריוגרפיה של הספרות העברית החדשה (Vantage point: Issues in the historiography of Modern Hebrew literature; Or Yehuda: Dvir, 2005), pp. 215–234</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Moked, “On the Surface” (on Orly Kastel-Blum and Etgar Keret), Achshav, Literature, Art, and Communications 67–68 (2002–2003): 302–303</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Moked, “On the Surface,” p. 305</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Moked, “On the Surface,” p. 305</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Kleinberg, “Existential Seasickness,” Haaretz, June 13, 2002</mixed-citation>. Online: http://www .haaretz.com/life/2.205/existential-seasickness-1.42421.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Kleinberg, “Existential Seasickness.”</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Kaniuk, “ כמו-אדישות שמחה שכועסת עמוק בשורשים, אך לא נואמת ” (A sort of happy indifference that has anger deep in its roots, but does not sermonize), Haaretz Books, December 16, 1998</mixed-citation>. This is not at all in line with the reservations of all the critics whose essays I have related to above.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <p>Emphasis added. Y. Kaniuk, “A Sort of Happy Indifference.” Kaniuk writes the last paragraph of the article in a typical revealing, personal tone: “I read and am jealous. When I did similar things, I was torn apart. Keret is taught in universities, and he will receive the Israel Prize. Keret is a star for those who love to read him, and they are many. For my part, Keret’s ability to express himself, like others of his age, is also a victory over my failure. Soon, when I get to the next world, I won’t get to where Keret’s protagonist does. Perhaps also because Rabbi Ovadia Yosef, the Chazon Ish of current Mizrahi Jewry, said that those who voted for Shas would get to heaven, and I voted for Keret” (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Kaniuk, “A Sort of Happy Indifference”</mixed-citation>).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Shklovsky, “ האושר הוא רגע גנוב וחולף ” (Happiness is a stolen, passing moment), Iton 77 268 (2002): 6</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “The Holocaust,” pp. 151–169</mixed-citation>.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Siren” was published in English in E. Keret, The Bus Driver Who Wanted to be God: And Other Stories (trans. M. Shlesinger; New York: Toby Press, 2004), pp. 72–76</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “The Holocaust,” p. 157</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “The Holocaust,” p. 157</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Guvrin, “The Holocaust,” p. 157</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Nagid, “ שירת הפרברים ” (Song of the Suburbs), Yedioth Achronoth, January 24, 1997, p. 29</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I. Tzivoni, “Some Comments,” pp. 24–26, 45. Y. Schwartz, “Upside-down Logic,” pp. 6, 13</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Akimoto, “Etgar Keret, Haruki Murakami and World Literature: The Possibility of Translation” (paper presented at the “Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Balaban, גל חדש בסיפורת העברית: סיפורת עברית פוסט-מודרנית (A new wave in Hebrew fiction: Postmodern Hebrew fiction; Jerusalem: Keter, 1995), pp. 54-56</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Gurevich, “Recycled Dreams,” Iton 77 194 (1996): 38–43</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Gurevich, Postmodernism, Culture, and Literature, pp. 287– 304</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Buchweitz, “The Evacuation of Character in Postmodernist Prose: The Case of Keret and Castel-Blum” (paper presented at the NAPH conference in Stanford, California in June 2005)</mixed-citation>.<mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. McHale, “A Map of Misreading, or, How Etgar Keret Got Postmodernism Wrong and Reinvented Israeli Fiction” (paper presented at the “Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">V. K. Shemtov, “Being Stuck in the Continuous Present: Etgar Keret and Contemporary Hebrew Literature” (paper presented at the “Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming)</mixed-citation>;<mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Katsman, “Etgar Keret’s Laughter: The Unbearable Lightness of Banality, or What is Israeli Humor?” (paper presented at the “ Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <p>An exception that proves the rule is Roman Katsman. See his<mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Mythopoesis, Ethics and Ideology: Stories by Etgar Keret” in Poetics of Becoming: Dynamic Processes of Mythopoesis in Modern and Postmodern Hebrew and Slavic Literature (Frankfurt am Main: Peter Lang, 2005), pp. 71– 97</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Benjamin, “The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction,” in Illuminations (ed. H. Arendt; New York: Schocken, 1968), pp. 217–251</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Cohen, “Poésie et reconance,” Poétique 28 (1976): 422–423</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <p>Prominent examples of this phenomenon may be found in the stories “Kneller’s Happy Campers” from Kneller’s Happy Campers and “Lieland” from Suddenly, A Knock at the Door. On parallel worlds in Etgar Keret’s works, see C. Merril, “Parallel Universes: The Worlds of Etgar Keret,” (paper presented at the “Etgar Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <p>The pattern, the joining of two hostile and integral poetical-philosophical moves and the confrontation between them, corresponds with the definition of repetition that Shlomith Rimmon-Kenan offers as a preparatory platform for the discussion of the poetics of repetition. Rimmon-Kenan presents the phenomenon of repetition by means of three paradoxes: 1) “Repetition is present everywhere and nowhere”; 2) “Constructive repetition emphasizes difference, destructive repetition emphasizes sameness (i.e., to repeat successfully is not to repeat)”; and 3) “The first time is already a repetition, and repetition is the very first time” (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Rimmon-Kenan, “The Paradoxical Status of Repetition,” Poetics Today 1.4 (1980): 151–159</mixed-citation>. Also see in this context<mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Rimmon-Kenan, “Doubles and Counterparts: Patterns of Interchangeability in Borges’ ‘The Garden of Forking Paths.’” Critical Inquiry 6.4 (Summer 1980): 639–647</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Jakobson, “The Dominant,” in Readings in Russian Poetics: Formalist and Structuralist Views (ed. M. Ladislav and K. Pomorska; Cambridge: MIT Press, 1971), pp. 82–87</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret, “Suddenly a Knock on the Door” (trans. M. Shlesinger), in Suddenly a Knock on the Door (New York: Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 2010), pp. 3–8</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret, “Missing Kissinger” (trans. M. Shlesinger), in Missing Kissinger (London: Vintage, 2005), p. 11</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret, “Missing Kissinger,” p. 11</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret, “Missing Kissinger,” p. 11</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret, “Missing Kissinger,” p. 14</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Kermode, The Sense of Ending (London: Oxford University Press, 1967)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <p>For example, in “Suddenly, A Knock on the Door,” it is the last story robber, the pizza delivery boy, who convinces the robber to give in to Keret the author, who will allow him to give up his opening mantra “suddenly, a knock on the door”: “‘Let him,’ the pizza guy says softly, ‘give him some slack. You want a knock on the door? Just so long as it brings us a story” (p. 8). Sometimes the character that sets this mechanism in motion does not belong to the story’s narrative present, although it becomes clear in retrospect that it has an important role in the interpretation of the story. Thus, for example, in the story before us, from whose opening paragraph it is clear that all the acts of robbing the narrator of a story echo a parallel story between a father and son: “Tell me a story,” the bearded man sitting on my living-room sofa commands. “The situation, I must say, is anything but pleasant. I’m someone who writes stories, not someone who tells them. And even that isn’t something I do on demand. The last time anyone asked me to tell him a story, it was my son. That was a year ago. I told him something about a fairy and a ferret—I don’t even remember what exactly—and within two minutes, he was fast asleep. But the situation is fundamentally different. Because my son doesn’t have a beard, or a pistol. Because my son asked for the story nicely, and this man is simply trying to rob me of it” (p. 3). A similar situation opens the chain of events in Streets of Rage: “When I was twelve my big brother took me to a movie about boxers” (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret and A. Hanuka, סמטאות הזעם [Streets of rage; Tel-Aviv: Zemorah-Bitan, 1997], p. 4</mixed-citation>), and that brother, like Keret’s son in “Suddenly, a Knock on the Door,” is never mentioned again in the story. On this phenomenon, from a different angle, see<mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Buchweitz, “Vitalities and Fatalities in Relationships in Keret’s Graphic Texts (Streets of Rage, Nobody Said it was Going to be Fun, Pizzeria Kamikaze),” (paper presented at the “Etgar Keret’s Happy Campers” conference at the University of Chicago, October 10–14, 2015, forthcoming)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <p>See for comparison<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Orian, “ יופי של גיהינום ” (A lovely hell; Yedioth Achronoth, February 28, 1992). p. 24</mixed-citation>. Yaron Peleg offers a suggestive analysis in which he points to the gap between the “flat” surface of Keret’s stories and their serious subject matter, the difficult mental states that echo through them, and the author’s deep criticism. Particularly interesting is his discussion regarding the relationship between the jackets of the books Pipelines and Missing Kissinger, which are naïve/kitschy in character and the essential character of the stories in them. See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Peleg, Israeli Culture, pp. 68–90</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Bergson, Laughter: An Essay on the Meaning of the Comic (trans. C. Brereton and F. Rothwell; New York: Macmillan, 1911)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <p>Emphasis added.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <p>Emphasis added.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <p>See<mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Hirschfeld, “ עיוות המרחב בגרוטסקה ב׳תמול שלשום׳ לש״י עגנון ” (Warped space in the grotesque in Only Yesterday), Jerusalem Studies in Hebrew Literature 15 (1981): 49–59</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <p>On the grotesque in Keret’s work, see<mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Mendelson-Maoz, “ סיטואציות קיצוניות זוועתיות וגרוטסקיות ביצירותיהם של קסטל-בלום וקרת ” (Extreme, horrific, and grotesque situations in the works of Castel-Bloom and Keret), Dapim le Mechkar be-Sifrut 11 (1997–1998): 269–295</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret and A. Hanuka, Streets of Rage</mixed-citation>. In a number of stories, Keret reveals the tactic that justifies his use of stereotypical racist labels. Thus, for example, in “ מונטאז׳ ” (Montage), in the graphic short story collection לא באנו להנות (Nobody said it was going to be fun; Jerusalem: Keter, 1996) by Keret and Rutu Modan, the story begins with four fragments in which Keret creates a labeling drama, each one of which on its own, and all of which together reflect a society that marks and attacks anyone who is perceived as other (p. 29). A similar mechanism of exposing the stereotypical racist approach to Arabs in Jewish Israeli society is used in פיצריה קמיקזה (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pizzeria kamikaze; Or Yehuda: Kinneret, 2004</mixed-citation>), the graphic novel adapted from Kneller’s Happy Campers, by Keret and Asaf Hanuka. At a certain stage of the story, two of the Jewish Israeli protagonists are driving to an unknown area. The following conversation takes place between them: Character A: “Look at this place. The sorts of people walking around here. Seriously. I don’t know why I came with you.” Character B: “Just because you don’t know them, that’s no reason to be paranoid.” Character A: “It’s not paranoia… everyone here is an Arab. I told you we should have driven north. Everyone knows all the sexy girls are in the north. In the east there is nothing except Mizrachim.” Character B: So what if they’re Arabs? Character A: Suicidal Arabs— that doesn’t make you a little nervous? What if they find out we’re Israeli?” (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Keret and A. Hanuka, Pizzeria Kamikaze, p. 35</mixed-citation>; emphases added). Keret created a brilliant labeling drama, based on the custom of calling people by animal names and on the literalization of some of those names, in “The Sad Story of the Anteater Family,” in the collection Missing Kissinger.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <p>In his analysis, Roman Katsman makes a connection between Etgar Keret’s “The Hollow Men” (from the collection Missing Kissinger), and the practice of linguistic repetition in an attempt to appropriate something that belongs to another. He notes, following Erik Gans, that “the very repetition of the words of the father by the hollow men amounts to the stealing of the voice, that is, it is appropriation” (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Katsman, “ געגועים למיתוס: אישיות, אתיקה ואידיאולוגיה במיתופואסיס הפוסטמודרני של אתגר קרת ” [Missing the myth: Personality, ethics and ideology in the postmodern mythopoesis of Etgar Keret], Mikan, January 4, 2005, p. 36</mixed-citation>). By the way, Udi Taub, in his monumental work יודאיקה (<mixed-citation publication-type="other">Judaica; Or Yehudah: Kinneret Zmora-Bitan, 2011</mixed-citation>), makes brilliant use of the praxis of reproduction, here the reproduction of durable products, as an attempt at both religious and commercial appropriation. See also<mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Gans, “Originary Narrative,” Anthropoetics: The Electronic Journal of Generative Anthropology 3.2 (1997–1998)</mixed-citation>. Online: http://www.anthropoetics.ucla.edu/ap0302/narrative.htm.</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
