<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="doi">10.5621</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">sciefictstud</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title content-type="full">Science Fiction Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SF-TH Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00917729</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23276207</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">sciefictstud.41.3.0481</article-id>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="doi">10.5621/sciefictstud.41.3.0481</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Supragenological Types of Fiction versus Contemporary Non-Mimetic Literature</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>Grzegorz Trębicki</string-name>
            </contrib>
            <bio>
               <p>
                  <bold>Grzegorz Trębicki</bold>teaches at Jan Kochanowski University, Kielce, Poland. His academic interests include non-mimetic literature (especially world fantasy) as well as theory and genology of literature. His articles and reviews have been published in<italic>The New York Review of Science Fiction, Extrapolation, Mythlore</italic>, and<italic>Science Fiction Studies.</italic>He is currently working on a book project entitled<italic>Worlds So Strange And Diverse: Towards A Genological Taxonomy of Non-Mimetic Literature.</italic>
               </p>
            </bio>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>November 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">41</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">sciefictstud.41.issue-3</issue-id>
         <fpage>481</fpage>
         <lpage>501</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2014 SF-TH Inc.</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5621/sciefictstud.41.3.0481"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This article elaborates on a model of supragenological types of fiction originally proposed by Andrzej Zgorzelski in the article “Is Science Fiction a Genre of Fantastic Literature?” (<italic>SFS</italic>6.3 [Nov. 1979]: 296–303). It attempts to apply his model as a tool of taxonomical description to contemporary non-mimetic (“fantastic”) fiction in all of its richness and diversity. In the initial part of the essay, Zgorzelski's theoretical assumptions are briefly summarized and explained. In the remainder of the essay, four non-mimetic supragenological categories—exomimetic literature, fantastic literature, antimimetic literature, and paramimetic literature—are discussed at some length and used as a source of reference for a preliminary analysis of a large group of texts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="parsed-citations">
         <title>Notes</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">By “non-mimetic” or “fantastic” fiction (or “fantasy” literature in its wider meaning—that is, including sf) I intend the broadest possible category that can be described with these denominations, encompassing all historical and contemporary genres and texts that—in terms of the methodology presented in the second section—do not pretend to imitate phenomenal (empirical) reality.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I purposely place the word “non-realistic” in inverted commas here and elsewhere (the same obviously applies for the word “realistic”) to emphasize that I refer only to their popular usage, but I do not perceive them as proper literary-theoretical terms (see Scholes's and Zgorzelski's statements quoted in the next section). Zgorzelski, while giving his arguments for renouncing the very notion of realism, remarks that it is based on an inadequate comparison between textual and empirical realities “and so disagrees with the autonomous nature of literature, the interest itself in such a comparison suggesting subversively that one of the aims of literature is to inform about the surrounding reality” (“Theoretical Preliminaries” 12).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The terms “genological” and “supragenological” are obviously constructed from “genus” and also refer to “literary genology” understood as “a systematic study of genres in a historical context” (Ostaszewska and Cudak 26–28). I realize the terms are not normally used in US or UK critical discourse, but I have decided to retain them as they are used extensively in Zgorzelski's original works. They could be, however, easily replaced by “generic” or “supergeneric,” respectively.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The notion of supragenological types of fiction was presented in<italic>SFS</italic>in 1979 in the article “Is Science Fiction a Genre of Fantastic Literature?” In this paper, however, I will refer to the most recent version of the article entitled “Fantastic Literature and Genre Systems” included in the collection<italic>Born of the Fantastic</italic>(reviewed in<italic>SFS</italic>4.1 by the author of this essay) and another article from the same collection, “Theoretical Preliminaries: on the Understanding of the Fantastic.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">This definition parallels Jackson's suggestion that the mimetic mode includes narratives “which claim to imitate an external reality” and to make “an implicit claim of equivalence between represented fictional world and the ‘real’ world outside the text” (33–34).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Making a sociological rather than literary-theoretical comment, we might risk the claim that exomimetic fiction also attracts the most distinct readership. An open rejection of the pretence of describing empirical reality probably discourages many readers who are culturally inclined to profess the traditional notion of the imitative functions of literature.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I refer here exclusively to “fantasy” texts set in a secondary world, that is to the works of J.R.R. Tolkien, Ursula K. Le Guin, Stephen R. Donaldson, Robert Jordan, Steven Erikson, and many similar authors. Secondary World Fantasy, Imaginary World Fantasy, or High Fantasy has been acknowledged as a separate class of texts by such critics as Carter, Tymn, Zahorski, Boyer, Mendlesohn, and Manlove.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">See, especially, Suvin's “Science Fiction.” In another article, Suvin even proposes an analogy comparing sf and fantasy to two “thermometers with mercury. One thermometer can go from zero to 100 degrees, the other, made for human bodies, only from 30 to 43 degrees centigrade. The bigger one is to me SF, the smaller one Fantasy” (“On Ursula K. Le Guin” 501).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">See Suvin's “On Ursula K. Le Guin” and Lem. The latter especially acknowledges the quality of Le Guin's speculativeness: “Do I want to say that Ursula Le Guin's fairy tale is more realistic [Lem's use of the word “realistic” is slightly unfortunate here; it could be, perhaps, replaced by “cognitive”] than her science fiction? Yes, exactly. Paradoxes such as these occur in literature— that the function of magic in one book proves more realistic than the function of a scientific invention in another book. But this paradox is only apparent. The text creates a world ruled by its own laws as an autonomous whole, and it is this overall coherence and not its particular fragments, for example terms borrowed from some scientific dictionary, that determines whether the text is realistic” (196). It is, however, quite remarkable that both critics seem to approve of Le Guin's swf novels because of the features that make these texts similar to science fiction.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Obviously, Le Guin's and Tolkien's models are very different ones, the former essentially based on a creative adaptation of Taoist principles, the latter on Christian good-evil dualism. Yet the function of world-making and its significance for the books' structures and messages is comparable.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Many of those works are discussed by Mendlesohn as typical examples of immersive fantasy. It seems that an “immersive” narrative strategy can be linked with this relatively recent stage of the evolution of exomimetic fiction and is characteristic for this supragenological type.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">This relatively recent strategy of seamlessly fusing sf and swf elements, resulting in the creation of a fictional world that can be perceived as a cognitive and genological novum, rather than merely a sum of both genre conventions, can be compared with a more traditional operation, typical for earlier texts of “science fantasy,” in which sf and swf motifs are easily distinguishable from each other within a given text and clearly juxtaposed. Le Guin's “Semley's Necklace” (1964) provides a good example here. The story consists of two alternating parts, written in conformity with sf and swf conventions. This earlier variant of science fantasy is predominantly characterized by the operation of the fantastic—a clash of the two world models represented by the respective conventions of sf and swf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Several critics do realize the distinction between the two groups of texts and try to subcategorize the works that are here referred to as “antimimetic.” For example, the<italic>Encyclopedia of Fantasy</italic>, probably the most complete and up-to-date publication of this type, proposes the label “contemporary fantasy,” which is described in a way that is at several points, at least, compatible with the assumptions presented in this paper (225). Tymn, Zahorski, and Boyer, in turn, distinguish between “high” fantasy, set in secondary worlds and “low fantasy” set in mimetic reality (5).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Many of Jackson's “subversive” fantasy texts could probably be placed in this category as well.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Making a more personal observation, it has never appealed to me (as, probably, to many other readers) to perceive the generic distance between, for example,<italic>The Left Hand of Darkness</italic>(1969) and<italic>A Wizard of Earthsea</italic>as greater than the distance between any of these novels and Lewis Carroll's<italic>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</italic>(1865) or Jonathan Carroll's<italic>Bones of the Moon.</italic>In fact, I believe, it is exactly the other way round: as considerably speculative texts,<italic>A Wizard of Earthsea</italic>and<italic>The Left Hand of Darkness</italic>have much more in common with each other (and it is not merely because they were written by the same author; we can substitute any sophisticated, contemporary secondary-world fantasy novel for the first and any “otherworldly” sf novel for the latter, and the result will be still very much the same).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">On the whole, it seems that the more a non-mimetic text tries to conceal its generic status, the more likely it is going to be accepted by the general reading public. Two main factors are probably responsible for this: first, the traditional system of literary evaluation, according to which “the more alike a fictional world of a novel is to our reality, the higher the novel is evaluated as a piece of art” (Zgorzelski, “Theoretical Preliminaries” 12); and, second, the fact that non-mimetic literature usually requires more reading competence in comparison to the most popular mimetic forms.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
      <ref-list content-type="parsed-citations">
         <title>Works Cited</title>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Carter, Lin</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Imaginary Worlds. The Art of Fantasy.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Ballantine</publisher-name>,<year>1973</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <article-title>“Contemporary Fantasy.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Encyclopedia of Fantasy.</italic>
               </source>Ed.<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>John Clute</string-name>
               </person-group>and<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>John Grant</string-name>
               </person-group>.:<publisher-name>St. Martin's</publisher-name>,<year>1999</year>.<fpage>225</fpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Fredericks, S.C.</string-name>
               </person-group>
               <article-title>“Problems of Fantasy.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>SFS</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>5.1</volume>(Mar.<year>1978</year>):<fpage>33</fpage>–<lpage>45</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Godshalk, William L.</string-name>
               </person-group>
               <article-title>“Alfred Bester: Science Fiction or Fantasy.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Extrapolation</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>16.2</volume>(<year>1975</year>):<fpage>149</fpage>–<lpage>55</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Jackson, Rosemary</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Fantasy: the Literature of Subversion.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>,<year>1991</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Lem, Stanisław</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Afterword.”</article-title>
               <person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Ursula K. Le Guin</string-name>
               </person-group>,<source>
                  <italic>Czarnoksiężnik z Archipelagu.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Wydawnictwo Literackie</publisher-name>,<year>1983</year>:<fpage>191</fpage>–<lpage>98</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Manlove, C.N.</string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>
                  <italic>The Fantasy Literature of England.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Macmillan</publisher-name>,<year>1999</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Martin, Philip</string-name>
               </person-group>, ed.<source>
                  <italic>The Writer's Guide to Fantasy Literature.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Writer</publisher-name>,<year>2002</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Mendlesohn, Farah</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Rhetorics of Fantasy.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Wesleyan UP</publisher-name>,<year>2008</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Ostaszewska, Dorota</string-name>
               </person-group>, and<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Romuald Cudak</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Polska Genologia Literacka.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Wydawnictwo Naukowe PWN</publisher-name>,<year>2007</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Rabkin, Eric S.</string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>
                  <italic>The Fantastic in Literature.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Princeton UP</publisher-name>,<year>1976</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Scholes, Robert</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Structural Fabulation: An Essay on the Future of Fiction.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>U of Notre Dame P</publisher-name>,<year>1975</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Suvin, Darko</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“On Ursula K. Le Guin's ‘Second Earthsea Trilogy’ and its Cognitions: A Commentary.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Extrapolation</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>47.3</volume>(<year>2006</year>):<fpage>488</fpage>–<lpage>504</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Suvin, Darko</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Science Fiction and the Genological Jungle.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Genre</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>6.3</volume>(<year>1973</year>):<fpage>251</fpage>–<lpage>273</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Todorov, Tzvetan</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>The Fantastic. A Structural Approach to a Literary Genre.</italic>
               </source>1970. Trans.<person-group person-group-type="translator">
                  <string-name>Richard Howard</string-name>
               </person-group>.:<publisher-name>Cornell UP</publisher-name>,<year>1975</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Trębicki, Grzegorz</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Fantasy. Ewolucja Gatunku.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Universitas</publisher-name>,<year>2007</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Trębicki, Grzegorz</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“The Fantastic and Genological Research.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>SFS</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>40.1</volume>(Mar.<year>2013</year>):<fpage>184</fpage>–<lpage>85</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Tymn, Marshall</string-name>
               </person-group>,<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Kenneth J. Zahorski</string-name>
               </person-group>, and<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Robert H. Boyer</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Fantasy: A Core Collection and Reference Guide.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Bowker</publisher-name>,<year>1979</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Zahorski, Kenneth J.</string-name>
               </person-group>, and<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Robert H. Boyer</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“The Secondary Worlds of High Fantasy.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>The Aesthetics of Fantasy Literature and Art.</italic>
               </source>Ed.<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Roger Schlobin</string-name>
               </person-group>.:<publisher-name>U of Notre Dame P</publisher-name>,<year>1982</year>:<fpage>56</fpage>–<lpage>80</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Zgorzelski, Andrzej</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Fantastic Literature and Genre Systems.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Born of the Fantastic</italic>
               </source>,:<publisher-name>Wydawnictwo Uniwersytetu Gdańskiego</publisher-name>,<year>2004</year>.<fpage>11</fpage>–<lpage>27</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Zgorzelski, Andrzej</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Fantastyka. Utopia. Science Fiction. Ze studiów nad rozwojem gatunków.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Państwowe Wydawnictwo Naukowe</publisher-name>,<year>1980</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Zgorzelski, Andrzej</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Is Science Fiction a Genre of Fantastic Literature?”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>SFS</italic>
               </source>
               <volume>6.3</volume>(Nov.<year>1979</year>):<fpage>296</fpage>–<lpage>303</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Zgorzelski, Andrzej</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Theoretical Preliminaries: on the Understanding of the Fantastic.”</article-title>
               <source>
                  <italic>Born of the Fantastic.</italic>
               </source>:<publisher-name>Wydawnictwo Uniwersytetu Gdańskiego</publisher-name>,<year>2004</year>.<fpage>28</fpage>–<lpage>41</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
