<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">globalsouth</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title content-type="full">The Global South</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Indiana University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19328648</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19328656</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">GSO.3.2.14</article-id>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="doi">10.2979/GSO.2009.3.2.14</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
               <subject>Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
            <subj-group subj-group-type="subject">
               <subject>Global studies</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Letter from an American Professor: An Asian American Education in the South</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ho</surname>
                  <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <month>October</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>Fall 2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">gso.2009.3.issue-2</issue-id>
         <fpage>14</fpage>
         <lpage>31</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2009 The University of Mississippi</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2009</copyright-year>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.2979/gso.2009.3.2.14"/>
         <abstract>
            <title>ABSTRACT</title>
            <p>As the field of Asian American studies has grown and developed, so too has the number of professors teaching Asian American studies content, particularly within the South. Diverting from the conventional format for academic writing, this paper offers a series of personal as well as professional observations on teaching Asian American studies in the South (at UNC). Responding to segments of Hector St. John de Crevecoeur's<italic>Letters from an American Farmer</italic>, I attempt to illuminate the nexus of abstract theory and lived experience, the episodes I relate demonstrating my own nascent theorizing on Asian American studies in the South and the multiple intersections I encounter as an Asian American woman teaching Asian American studies in the U.S. South.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="parsed-citations">
         <title>Notes</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I claim a national identity for myself as “American” (unhyphenated, unqualified) because in the spirit of de Crevecoeur I believe that I am an American, because I was born in the U.S. (New York City specifically) and raised with American social and cultural norms. Although I do claim a racial identity as an Asian American and an ethnic identity as a Chinese American, for the purposes of this essay and in the spirit of older models of Asian American literary criticism a la Sau-ling Cynthia Wong by way of Maxine Hong Kingston, I too claim America as my own.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I recognize that the region of “the South” is much more diverse and complex than a simple regional rendering suggests, yet the phrase “the South,” has been used in the public imagination and in various types of American discourses (political, social, cultural) as a shorthand that provides a useful parallel to the term “Asian American,” which has similar complex and competing definitions due to its inherent diversity. Furthermore, I will not be using scare quotes around either the term “the South” or “Asian American” for the duration of this essay.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Although there is a tendency in American literature to read de Crevecoeur's<italic>Letters</italic>as autobiography, I agree with Edward Larkin, and others, that this work should be read as a fictional accounting rather than a strictly representational relating of de Crevecoeur's life; as Larkin notes: “It is a mark of the success of this particular fiction that critics have often treated its representations as factual accounts of the social and cultural landscape of Revolutionary America, but to read this work as anything other than a fiction is to miss the central point of the text” (<fpage>54</fpage>).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">For more on the history of Asian American studies as a discipline, see<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>William Wei</string-name>
               </person-group>'s<source>
                  <italic>The Asian American Movement</italic>
               </source>and<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Sucheng Chan</string-name>
               </person-group>'s<source>
                  <italic>In Defense of Asian American Studies: the Politics of Teaching and Program Building</italic>
               </source>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">As of December 9, 2008, the on-line directory of the Association of Asian American Studies listed 36 members of the following Southern states: Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, North Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, and Virginia. This figure of 36 members only means that these individuals paid dues to the Association for Asian American studies and not that these are faculty members teaching Asian American content courses or graduate students conducting research in Asian American studies. However, a cursory look at the names and university affiliations does suggest that at least twothirds of these members are either faculty members in tenure-track positions or graduate students in PhD programs. This figure does not also include graduate students or faculty members who have chosen not to join AAAS. Therefore the figure of 36 must be understood within these contingencies. One additional note: the states of Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi, and South Carolina were not listed among the membership rolls of AAAS; in other words, in the pull-down menu on the AAAS directory, these states were not listed as searchable options. In private email correspondence (Dec. 9, 2008) with Vladimir Micic, an administrator with the Association for Asian American Studies, he confirmed that as of the October membership rolls, there were no members in the Southern region of the U.S. from those states out of the 707 active members affiliated with AAAS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I will be abbreviating The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill to UNC Chapel Hill throughout the remainder of this essay.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">There is some dispute over the title of “oldest public university” in the United States. The University of Georgia had its charter in 1785, four years before the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill would receive its charter. However, UGA did not matriculate its first students until 1801, whereas UNC Chapel Hill opened its doors to students in 1795. However, both universities are eclipsed by the College of William and Mary, whose charter dates back to 1693; yet William and Mary, though now a university, began its life as a “college,” thus making it the oldest public college in the United States, whereas UGA and UNC Chapel Hill enjoy competition over the oldest public university in the U.S., depending on whether one considers the dates of their charters versus dates of matriculation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Both places, UNC Chapel Hill and Chapel Hill, NC, are considered very “liberal” places from the point-of-view of North Carolinians as well as Southerners in general. One of the most well-known quotes about its liberal atmosphere came from the infamous conservative senator, Jesse Helms, who said that North Carolina didn't need a state zoo because all you had to do was put a fence around UNC Chapel Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">When I had once remarked to a senior African American faculty member that I felt Asian Americans were both an underrepresented and misunderstood minority group in North Carolina, my colleague agreed but also pointed out that for all intents and purposes, Asian Americans were “white.” I voiced my dissent from my colleague, but I do not know that it made any difference in changing an attitude that I think is prevalent among many in the South.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">While the racial discourse of the South has largely been along a white-black axis, slowly other racial groups are asserting their presence, most notably the indigenous populations of North Carolina, the Lumbee and Cherokee, as well as the expanding Latino population. And Asian Americans, while often invisible and unrecognized within North Carolina, are making their mark through professional organizations such as local chapters of the National Asian American Professionals Association and a group organized by the Chapel Hill school district of parents of Asian American students.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Of course, my own reaction may have been mediated by the fact that these interactions occurred between myself and pairs of African American Southerners rather than white Southerners.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I am most often mistaken as “Hawaiian” when people have tried to guess where I'm “from”—and all my interrogators thus far have been white men with Southern accents, two odd coincidences but true.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I must be honest and admit that I haven't been subjected to a greater number of inquiries here in the South than in other places in the country, at least places outside of California. Indeed, I receive similar inquiries from people I encountered living in both Boston and Western Massachusetts.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The most recent presidential addresses by past presidents of the Association of American Studies, Shelly Fisher Fishkin and Emory Elliot, have discussed the exciting and innovative direction of scholarship with American Studies to consider transnational and diasporic issues within American Studies, and to consider scholarship in American Studies outside the borders of the U.S., in terms of our colleagues in other nations and continents. Furthermore, innovative research by scholars of Asian American studies are looking at themes of cosmopolitanism and transnationalism. Indeed, a panel at the most recent East of California conference (October 31-November 1, 2008), the panel “Transnationalism and Asian/Asian American Studies” specifically addressed this intersection.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Among the most prevalent title to come up with students and faculty alike when queried about what Asian American work they have previous read is Amy Tan's<italic>Joy Luck Club</italic>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The most recent example of this confusion occurred when a colleague from another department advised a graduate student to have me on his comprehensive exam committee because his future dissertation will be looking at Vietnamese literature during the period of French colonialism. I patiently explained to the student that I am not an Asian Studies scholar and that while I am familiar with Vietnamese American authors, I am neither fluent in Vietnamese nor French, and I do not study Vietnamese literature.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">For three years, 2000-2003, I taught as a visiting instructor at Mount Holyoke College, originally arriving there on a pre-doctoral dissertation fellow and staying on as a visiting instructor, and eventually visiting Assistant Professor once I received my PhD in January 2003 from Boston University. I credit Mount Holyoke College for beginning my professional development as an Asian American teacher and scholar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The films<italic>Slaying the Dragon</italic>and<italic>The Slanted Screen</italic>are excellent documentaries charting this stereotype in American cinema.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I should note that, technically speaking, I first came to UNC Chapel Hill in July 2003 on a post-doctoral fellowship, which allowed me to teach one class each year. However, for the purposes of “counting,” I am starting with the time I was officially hired in a tenure-track position at UNC Chapel Hill, which also includes a year's research leave I took 2007-2008, which means that the above accounting of courses is over the span of three academic year cycles.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholars I admire who do research in Asian Americans in the South include Moon-Ho Jung, Carl Bankston, Elena Tajima Creef, and Leslie Bow. Certainly there are many others, but these scholars, in particular, have written works that have helped clarify and push my thinking about the intersections of Asian American and Southern studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">Indeed, in addition to this essay I have published an article on Asian American literature in the South called<article-title>“Southern Eruptions in Asian American Narratives,”</article-title>forthcoming in the collection edited by<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Jigna Desai</string-name>
               </person-group>and<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Khyati Joshi</string-name>
               </person-group>,<source>
                  <italic>Asian Americans in the New South</italic>
               </source>(<publisher-name>University of Georgia Press</publisher-name>).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">Personal interview,<month>September</month>
               <day>24</day>,<year>2008</year>,.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">English professor<person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Lisa Yun</string-name>
               </person-group>'s<source>
                  <italic>The Coolie Speaks: Chinese Indentured Laborers and African Slaves in Cuba</italic>
               </source>is among the latest innovative scholarship that looks at these intersections.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Historian and sociologists who have looked at the roles of Asian Americans in Southern history include Moon-Ho Jung, Robert Seto Quan, and Carl Bankston.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
      <ref-list content-type="parsed-citations">
         <title>Works Cited</title>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Cecelski, David</string-name>
               </person-group>. Personal Interview.,<month>September</month>
               <day>24</day>,<year>2008</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Christian, Barbara</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“The Race for Theory,”</article-title>in<source>
                  <italic>Gender and Theory: Dialogues on Feminist Criticism</italic>
               </source>, ed.<person-group person-group-type="editor">
                  <string-name>Linda Kauffman</string-name>
               </person-group>.:<publisher-name>Basil Blackwell</publisher-name>,<year>1989</year>.<fpage>225</fpage>-<lpage>37</lpage>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>de Crevecoeur, J. Hector St. John</string-name>
               </person-group>.<source>
                  <italic>Letters from an American Farmer and Sketches of Eighteenth-Century America</italic>
               </source>. (<year>1782</year>).:<publisher-name>Penguin Books</publisher-name>,<year>1963</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>Larkin, Edward</string-name>
               </person-group>.<article-title>“Cosmopolitan Revolution: Loyalism and the Fiction of an American Nation.”</article-title>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <source>
                  <italic>The Novel: A Forum on Fiction</italic>
               </source>.<volume>40</volume>:<issue>1</issue>(<season>Fall</season>
               <year>2006</year>-<season>Spring</season>
               <year>2007</year>):<fpage>52</fpage>-<lpage>76</lpage>.<publisher-name>Micic, Vladimir</publisher-name>. Personal email correspondence.<month>December</month>
               <day>9</day>,<year>2008</year>.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
